<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Texas Walkabout</title>
    <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com" />
    <updated>2022-02-19T10:57:13-06:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://texaswalkabout.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>How to get a stuck cowboy boot off? (Explained)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/how-to-get-a-stuck-cowboy-boot-off/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/how-to-get-a-stuck-cowboy-boot-off/</id>

        <updated>2022-02-19T10:57:13-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    How to get a stuck cowboy boot off If you are wondering how to get a stuck cowboy boot off of your leg, then you have come to the right place. This can be one of the most frustrating and uncomfortable things when it comes&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h2 class="p1">How to get a stuck cowboy boot off</h2>
<p class="p1">If you are wondering how to get a stuck cowboy boot off of your leg, then you have come to the right place. This can be one of the most frustrating and uncomfortable things when it comes to putting clothes on.</p>
<p>The reason is because the weather usually when you first get your pair of boots, is very stiff and is not comfortable at all to put your feet in and out of.<strong> In order to get your a cowboy boots off your foot and leg, you’ll want to grab the heel of the boot and probably slide it down word while arch in your foot upwards or downwards.</strong></p>
<p>You should noticed that as you do that, <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/wear-cowboy-boots-with-or-without-socks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the boot will begin to properly slight off and your heel will slide upward allowing you to shuttle your entire foot and leg out of the boot.</a></p>
<p class="p1">Again, this is not that fun to do, but as you start to wear them a lot more often, then you should notice that the weather actually starts to break in and the boots are not that hard to wear anymore. Let’s take a quick look though, at whether or not they are supposed to be this hard to takeoff.</p>
<h2 class="p1">Are cowboy boots supposed to be hard to take off?</h2>
<p class="p1">In general, whenever you purchase a new pair of leather cowboy boots, you should always expect them to be rather stiff and hard to slide on and off.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1"><strong>The leather is basically brand new, and it needs to be weathered down somewhat in order for it to become more malleable. By wearing your boots out and around town, you should notice that eventually, they will become a lot more comfortable to wear in general, and you are able to put them on and off with ease.</strong></p>
<p class="p1">Just keep on wearing them and eventually he will love to wear cowboy boots everywhere you go. <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/what-color-cowboy-hat-to-wear-with-brown-boots/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Then only that, they can be rather stylish depending on which ones you get. Let’s take a quick look again at how you get these tight little boots off your feet.</a></p>
<h2>How do you get tight boots off?</h2>
<p class="p1"><strong>In order to properly get tight boots off, you’ll want to grab the heel, and promptly pull it away from your actual heel in a downward motion. </strong></p>
<p>As you do this, curl your feet downward, exposing your actual heel in an upward position that is opposite to the direction you are pulling the boot.</p>
<p><a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/how-to-keep-cowboy-boots-from-rubbing-leg/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">You will notice that the hill actually starts to slide away from you, allowing you to escape your foot.</a></p>
<p class="p1">If you don’t want to do this manually yourself, then you can use a little tool that we will talk about in the next section of this article.</p>
<h2>What do you call the thing that helps you take boots off?</h2>
<p class="p1"><strong>The thing that helps you take boots off is known as a cowboy boot jack.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></strong></p>
<p class="p1"><strong>You basically just slide it down the shaft of the boot until it hits the bottom of the boot heel next to your actual heel.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></strong></p>
<p class="p1">This allows you to manually pry open the shaft of the boot to allow your leg and foot to escape the leather. It’s quite effective, it is something you should consider as you start to wear your brand new pair of boots all around town.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">It really is not that comfortable the feeling having very tight boots, but just rest assured that as you start to wear them everywhere, you’ll notice that they start to soften up on you.</p>
<h2>How can I soften my cowboy boots?</h2>
<p class="p1">If you want to really try and soften up your boots, I recommend only doing so naturally. <strong><a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/how-to-keep-cowboy-boots-from-rubbing-leg/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The best way to naturally soften your cowboy boots is to put them on and where them basically wherever you go.</a> </strong></p>
<p>This will allow the leather to begin weathering down, obtaining some moisture, and overtime slowly forming to your profile of your foot and leg. You can manually try to stretch your boots, but that is not recommended since you may be doing more harm than good by overstretching them and possibly tearing the leather.</p>
<h2 class="p1">Final Thoughts</h2>
<p class="p1"><strong>Getting cowboy boots off your foot can be an uncomfortable task, especially if they are tight and not that pleasant to wear. In order to properly get them off just grab heel and put away from your actual heel while arching your foot either upwards or downwards to let the boot slowly slide off. You can use a cowboy boot jack in order to expedite this process.</strong></p>
<p class="p1"> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to keep cowboy boots from rubbing leg? (Explained!)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/how-to-keep-cowboy-boots-from-rubbing-leg/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/how-to-keep-cowboy-boots-from-rubbing-leg/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-02-19T10:39:04-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    How to keep cowboy boots from rubbing leg? If you're wondering how to keep your cowboy boots from rubbing against your leg, then you've come to the right place. Having your leg be rubbed raw from some leather cowboy boots is no fun. In order&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h2>How to keep cowboy boots from rubbing leg?</h2>
<p>If you're wondering how to keep your cowboy boots from rubbing against your leg, then you've come to the right place. <strong>Having your leg be rubbed raw from some leather cowboy boots is no fun. In order to prevent this from happenind, you'll have to wear very long socks that go all the way up to your knees, and give the boots ample time to break in. </strong></p>
<p>Over the course of several wearing sessions, you should start to notice that your boots will start to become a lot more comfortable and tolerable as you walk around.</p>
<p>Speaking of breaking in cowboy boots, let's take a quick look at how to do that really fast so you can stop them from rubbing against your leg!</p>
<h2>How do you break in cowboy boots fast?</h2>
<p>Let's talk about how to break in cowboy boots fast and effectively. <strong>The simple solution is frankly to start wearing them all over the place. Wearing cowboy boots is the most natural way of letting them quickly form to the size of your feet and calves. </strong></p>
<p>The leather material that cowboy boots are made from is initially quite stiff, but over time it becomes soft and maleable. This means that as you make it a habit of just wearing them all around town, they will very quickly start to loosen up quite a bit </p>
<p>Having cowboy boots loosen up on you will feel great, and certainly protect your legs from the constant irritation of having the leather hit your extremeties.</p>
<p>Now that we've briefly covered how you can quickly break in your boots to properly adjust to your leg, let's take a quick look as to why your boots may be hard to fit into intitially. </p>
<h2>Why do some cowboy boots rub against your leg?</h2>
<p>If you're wondering why some cowboy boots may be rubbing against your leg, the reasoning is quite simple. <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/cowboy-boots-with-suit/">I<strong>t's just that as you purchase a new pair, they are essentially made of a stiff type of leather that takes a lot of conditioning by wearing them around all over.</strong></a></p>
<p>This means that the leather is very hard to fit even your feet into them at least at first glance, but over time the leather will start to obtain moisture and overall wear to them that will make them very easy to stretch.</p>
<p>Speaking of stretching you boots out, let's answer the qeustion as to how you can go about doing so.</p>
<h2 id="exacc_9BYRYsz-Or23qtsP_t2MgA83" class="iDjcJe IX9Lgd wwB5gf">How can I stretch the calf of my cowboy boots?</h2>
<p><strong>In order to properly break in and stretch out the calf of your cowboy boots, simply try wearing them everywhere you go.</strong> This may seem obvious, but is the most natural way of letting them properly form to your particular size and shape of legs and feet. </p>
<p>There are probably some aftermarket and manual ways of trying to stretch out the leather of your boots, but you run the risk of either over stretching or even ripping your boots apart.</p>
<p>Always go the natural route!</p>
<h2>Final thoughts</h2>
<p>If you're tired of having your cowboy boots rubbing against your leg, then have no fear.</p>
<p><strong>One of the most simple fixes to this issue is simply just wear them practically everywhere you go. This is the most natural and efficient way of letting them form to your individual profile.</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Is Boerne lake open to the public? (Explained)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/is-boerne-lake-open-to-the-public/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/is-boerne-lake-open-to-the-public/</id>
            <category term="Towns"/>

        <updated>2022-02-18T21:16:40-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                     Boerne lake is open to the general citizens of Boerne, Tx. Due to the influx of people flocking to Texas, Boerne Lake admins usually will make you present your Texas Drivers License to verify you are indeed a Boerne Resident. If you don’t happen&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Is Boerne lake open to the public</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Boerne lake is open to the general citizens of Boerne, Tx. Due to the influx of people flocking to Texas, Boerne Lake admins usually will make you present your Texas Drivers License to verify you are indeed a Boerne Resident.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you don’t happen to have a state drivers license that depicts you living in Boerne, you may not be allowed in. This is to preserve the authenticity and integrity of the lake, and prevent over crowding from people living in San Antonio coming up to enjoy some water activities.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:separator --></p>
<hr class="wp-block-separator"><!-- /wp:separator -->
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Can I swim at Boerne Lake?</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Boerne lake is open to all residents of Boerne, and allows people visiting to enjoy non motorized activities out on the water. The reason why no motorized activities are allowed, is because the lake serves as a reservoir  for domestic purposes of the City of Boerne. Having a lake dedicated for domestic purposes indicates that it is a protected area that needs to have as little contaminates as possible.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Despite not being able to have any motorized activity out on the lake, feel free to bring your paddle boards, kayaks, and other tubing devices and enjoy wading out on the lake in the middle of the Texas Hill Country!</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:separator --></p>
<hr class="wp-block-separator"><!-- /wp:separator -->
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Are there alligators in Boerne City Lake?</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>There are no known native species of alligators in Boerne City Lake. Despite this, there apparently have been reported sightings and catchings of some alligators that some suspect were dumped in nearby riverbeds.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>For the most part, there are no gators present in Boerne lake, or any other lake within the central Texas region of Texas. If you want to find gators, head on over to east Texas, where it is known that gators are native.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:separator --></p>
<hr class="wp-block-separator"><!-- /wp:separator -->
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>What kind of fish are in Boerne Lake?</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>There are a variety of species of fish at Boerne lake, including:</strong></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Bass</li>
<li>Catfish</li>
<li>Sunfish</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Here’s a link for more information:</strong></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><a href="https://tpwd.texas.gov/fishboat/fish/action/waterecords.php?WB_code=0092">https://tpwd.texas.gov/fishboat/fish/action/waterecords.php?WB_code=0092</a></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:separator --></p>
<hr class="wp-block-separator"><!-- /wp:separator -->
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Where is Boerne Lake located?</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image {"id":1279,"sizeSlug":"large","linkDestination":"none"} --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><figure class="wp-image-1279"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/6/Screen-Shot-2021-12-09-at-11.23.24-AM-1-1024x689.png" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/6/responsive/Screen-Shot-2021-12-09-at-11.23.24-AM-1-1024x689-xs.png 300w ,https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/6/responsive/Screen-Shot-2021-12-09-at-11.23.24-AM-1-1024x689-sm.png 480w ,https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/6/responsive/Screen-Shot-2021-12-09-at-11.23.24-AM-1-1024x689-md.png 768w ,https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/6/responsive/Screen-Shot-2021-12-09-at-11.23.24-AM-1-1024x689-lg.png 1024w ,https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/6/responsive/Screen-Shot-2021-12-09-at-11.23.24-AM-1-1024x689-xl.png 1360w ,https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/6/responsive/Screen-Shot-2021-12-09-at-11.23.24-AM-1-1024x689-2xl.png 1600w"  alt=""></figure></figure>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Boerne Lake is located on the northwest side of Boerne, right across from I-10. If you’re driving from Main Street, it’s only about a 5 Minute drive. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>When you’re driving on over to the lake, don’t forget to enjoy the scenery of the area, since that’s where a lot of the hills are. If you drive past the Boerne Lake entrance, you’ll be on this little two lane road that takes you deep into the Texas hill country, and can make for some epic views.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cowboy Boots With Suit | Can It Be Done?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/cowboy-boots-with-suit/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/cowboy-boots-with-suit/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-02-18T21:16:51-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                     Wearing cowboy boots with a suit is one of the easiest ways to class up your look. For a formal event, you can wear dress boots that are made out of black leather or brown leather with a nice shine. If you want to&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2><strong>Is it OK to wear cowboy boots with a suit?</strong></h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Wearing cowboy boots with a suit is one of the easiest ways to class up your look. For a formal event, you can wear dress boots that are made out of black leather or brown leather with a nice shine. If you want to add some more personality to your outfit, try some boots that are made out of a different material such as gator or ostrich.</strong></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You don't want your boots to be too cowboy-like, such as those that feature intricate stitching or large metal decorations on them. This would make your outfit seem more like something you'd wear when out on the town on the weekend rather than something for work or a formal event. You also don't want to go for any boots that have a toe that is too rounded or pointed. You want to aim for something in the middle where it will look good but also still give you comfort when you're wearing it.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>There are several different places where you can get these types of boots from, such as stores in big malls and even online stores. You'll find many different brands and styles when you shop around so it is important to take some time and find the best pair available to fit your needs.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:separator --></p>
<hr class="wp-block-separator"><!-- /wp:separator -->
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2><strong>Can you wear brown cowboy boots with black suit?</strong></h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Wearing a suit to the office is pretty standard, yet you can further dress it up by wearing cowboy boots. You can also make a cowboy boots with suit combination work for casual events.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>It will depend on the occasion, your location and the venue. If you are heading to a bar or nightclub, then you can wear any style of cowboy boots. If you are headed to an upscale party at a nice country club, then be sure to wear dress boots with your suit.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:separator --></p>
<hr class="wp-block-separator"><!-- /wp:separator -->
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2><strong>Can you wear cowboy boots to the office?</strong></h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>In the modern work environment, most people dress up to varying degrees. Women tend to wear dresses or skirts with nice tops, while men often wear nice slacks with a dress shirt and tie. In the business world, there are always some people who stand out by dressing too informally for the occasion.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>A pair of cowboy boots can be a great way to draw attention to yourself if you're aiming for that kind of effect — but what about if you're trying to fit in? Cowboy boots are associated with cowboys, which is an occupation that doesn't exactly scream "corporate professional."</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>However, this doesn't mean that cowboy boots have no place in a business setting. The key is dressing them up a bit so they don't look too casual. If you want to wear cowboy boots at the office, make sure they're dark brown or black and made from soft leather. Avoid things that look like they'd be more appropriate on a ranch than in an office building. Leave your jeans and cowboy hats at home unless you're headed straight from work to a country music concert.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:separator --></p>
<hr class="wp-block-separator"><!-- /wp:separator -->
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Can cowboy boots be considered dress shoes?</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Cowboy boots are definitely able to be considered dress shoes. You see in the wild west cowboys used to wear them all the time, but then they became a part of the country's culture and were worn by many people.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Boot makers started to make nicer versions of them and now they are a part of any fashion conscious man's wardrobe. Cowboy boots have a lot of fashion history behind them, and can be considered dress shoes if you get a nice pair that's not worn and old.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The best brands to go for really expensive cowboy boots from are Lucchese, which is an American brand that makes very high quality boots. They're very expensive but if you can afford it then they're worth getting because of their quality. For the more affordable version, try getting a pair from Tony Lama who makes some good boots at decent prices. If you'd like to go even cheaper than that, there are plenty of places online where you can get cheap ones as well.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>What color cowboy hat to wear with brown boots? (Explained)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/what-color-cowboy-hat-to-wear-with-brown-boots/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/what-color-cowboy-hat-to-wear-with-brown-boots/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-02-18T21:17:00-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                     One of the most important things to consider when choosing a hat is deciding on the color. The color of your hat depends on the color of your boots and shirt as well as the style of your outfit. If you wear a brown&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2><strong>what color cowboy hat to wear with brown boots</strong></h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>One of the most important things to consider when choosing a hat is deciding on the color. The color of your hat depends on the color of your boots and shirt as well as the style of your outfit. If you wear a brown cowboy hat with a brown shirt and brown boots, you will look like a "one trick pony" and it will detract from your overall appearance.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>To choose a hat that matches, you want to pick colors that are close but not exact. For example, if you are wearing brown boots and belt and a tan or light-colored shirt, then you would want to wear a black cowboy hat. Black is always an appropriate color for a man's western hat. If you wear black boots, skip the black hat in favor of one in another color such as blue or brown.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This way, your outfit won't have an over-all western appearance but instead it will appear stylish and well-put together.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:separator --></p>
<hr class="wp-block-separator"><!-- /wp:separator -->
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2><strong>What color goes with brown cowboy boots?</strong></h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Brown is a neutral color, which means that it's not going to clash with any other colors. However, some colors will look better with brown than others. Just like you can wear blue jeans with almost anything, you can pair brown boots with just about any color of clothing.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>For example, if you were wearing a blue shirt and a brown belt, you could wear the same exact blue shirt and the same brown belt with blue jeans without looking too weird. But if the shirt was red or green, the outfit would just look strange together.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:separator --></p>
<hr class="wp-block-separator"><!-- /wp:separator -->
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2><strong>How do you match a cowboy hat?</strong></h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>There are many things to think about when we want to match a cowboy hat. The most important thing is the color of your boots, and then you can choose a hat that matches that boot's color.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>A black hat goes well with brown or black boots. A gray hat also can go well with brown or black boots. A tan hat will match well with brown, black or tan boots. A white hat can go with any color boot! I have always been told that a white hat goes with everything, and it does! You can wear it anywhere and look great!</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:separator --></p>
<hr class="wp-block-separator"><!-- /wp:separator -->
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2><strong>When can you wear a black cowboy hat?</strong></h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>With a black cowboy hat, most people tend to wear it for a more formal setting, such as a wedding. If you are going to wear a black cowboy hat with brown boots, you would want to wear a more formal outfit such as a suit. That being said, there are some people who like to mix things up and do not feel as though they have to abide by the rules.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>With that in mind, if you would like to wear a black cowboy hat with brown boots, then do it! Mixing things up can be fun. Just make sure that your outfit is appropriate for the situation.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Should You Wear cowboy boots with or without socks? (Explained)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/wear-cowboy-boots-with-or-without-socks/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/wear-cowboy-boots-with-or-without-socks/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-02-18T21:17:09-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                     If you're wondering what you should do regarding wearing socks or not when wearing a pair of boots - you've come to the right place! In general, you will want to always consider wearing socks with your boots. That means wearing socks for both&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:heading {"textAlign":"center"} --></p>
<h2 class="has-text-align-center">Wear cowboy boots with or without socks?</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p class="has-text-align-center">If you're wondering what you should do regarding wearing socks or not when wearing a pair of boots - you've come to the right place!</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>In general, you will want to always consider wearing socks with your boots. That means wearing socks for both Chelsea and Cowboy style boots with longer shafts. Most boots are made of coarse leather, which is prone to moisture damage, bad smells, and a myriad of other things. Therefore, you don't want to taint your classy looking outfit by forgetting to put your socks on!</strong></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image {"align":"center","id":1222,"sizeSlug":"large","linkDestination":"none"} --></p>
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><figure class="wp-image-1222"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/2/IMG_3499-768x1024.jpeg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/2/responsive/IMG_3499-768x1024-xs.jpeg 300w ,https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/2/responsive/IMG_3499-768x1024-sm.jpeg 480w ,https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/2/responsive/IMG_3499-768x1024-md.jpeg 768w ,https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/2/responsive/IMG_3499-768x1024-lg.jpeg 1024w ,https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/2/responsive/IMG_3499-768x1024-xl.jpeg 1360w ,https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/2/responsive/IMG_3499-768x1024-2xl.jpeg 1600w"  alt=""></figure>
<figcaption>My new pair of Lucchese Boots</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:separator --></p>
<hr class="wp-block-separator"><!-- /wp:separator -->
<p><!-- wp:heading {"textAlign":"center"} --></p>
<h2 class="has-text-align-center">Should you wear cowboy boots without socks?</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p class="has-text-align-center">It is always recommended to wear a pair of socks with your cowboy boots. The reasoning behind this is simply that the shaft will start to irritate your skin as soon as you try and wear a pair of boots without any socks. When you don't wear socks, the boot leather will start to rub against your leg, causing a lot of irritation. You don't want that.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p class="has-text-align-center">When wearing boots, you want it to be as comfortable as possible. Also ask yourself the question, why would you honestly even consider wearing a pair of boots without any socks? This will just further ruin the experience.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p class="has-text-align-center">Not to mention, when you start walking around, you may begin to sweat quite a bit and make the leather stink.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:separator --></p>
<hr class="wp-block-separator"><!-- /wp:separator -->
<p><!-- wp:heading {"textAlign":"center"} --></p>
<h2 class="has-text-align-center">Are you supposed to wear socks with boots?</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>You are always supposed to wear socks with boots. Not only are you supposed to be wearing socks, they should be long socks that go all the way up past your calve. That's simply because of the elongated shaft of many boots that people wear. </strong></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p class="has-text-align-center">You can find boot styled socks anywhere that sells cowboy boots. Usually, it is relatively thick material that is able to withstand a lot of friction from the shaft part of the boot.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:separator --></p>
<hr class="wp-block-separator"><!-- /wp:separator -->
<p><!-- wp:heading {"textAlign":"center"} --></p>
<h2 class="has-text-align-center">Thick or thin socks with cowboy boots</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>If you're trying to decide on thick or thin socks to wear with your cowboy boots, always try to go for the thicker cut of socks. They're usually more durable and can retain heat better if you happen to be wearing it out in the cold. There's really no downside for thick cut socks. </strong></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p class="has-text-align-center">Thin socks on the other hand, are frankly a lot harder to be higher quality. They don't last as long, and if you happen to be out in the elements, then you will certainly be more exposed.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"textAlign":"center","level":3} --></p>
<h3 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color has-theme-palette-1-color">Quality of the sock</span></h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>The quality of your boot socks matter. That's because they need to withstand the constant friction of rubbing against the elongated shaft of the boot. Not only that, but just in general, thicker material will just last longer. There's more room for the fabric to start degrading. </strong></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p class="has-text-align-center">When you just have a thin little piece of fabric that you call a sock, once it starts eroding away - you're not left with a whole lot.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p class="has-text-align-center">Whenever you're in the store, just grab a nice, thick pair of boot styled socks to save yourself a lot of headache down the road.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:separator --></p>
<hr class="wp-block-separator"><!-- /wp:separator -->
<p><!-- wp:heading {"textAlign":"center"} --></p>
<h2 class="has-text-align-center">Best socks to wear with cowboy boots</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p class="has-text-align-center">The best socks to wear with cowboy boots are ones that are very comfortable, thick in quality, and match the coloring of your boots specifically.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Whenever you’re out shopping for some socks to wear with your cowboy boots, make sure to always grab quality material. This is the most critical part of buying socks that can withstand the coarse nature of the leather shaft of the boot. Having thick and great quality socks to wear with your boots allows for a longer shelflife. </strong></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p class="has-text-align-center">Like with most things, you don’t want to always have to buy a lot of different clothes just for the sake of buying clothes. You want to think of buying your socks as an investment and not a cost. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p class="has-text-align-center">Even though they’re thicker quality and are probably a lot more expensive than thinner types of socks, rest assured that you will hardly ever need to buy socks again for your boots.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p class="has-text-align-center">If you’re into style and want to present yourself in an excellent way, consider getting boot socks that match the leather coloring of your boots. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p class="has-text-align-center">Even though for the most part, you will never be able to see them because of the long shaft of the boot, it still looks really cool if you ever happened to roll your jeans or pants up to where others can see the coloring of your socks. Having matching clothes is always a plus.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:separator --></p>
<hr class="wp-block-separator"><!-- /wp:separator -->
<p><!-- wp:heading {"textAlign":"center"} --></p>
<h2 class="has-text-align-center">Socks that stay up in boots</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Finally, you’ll want to not only get socks that look cool and that are of high-quality, but you will also want to obtain socks that are relatively comfortable. For the most part, boots are not that comfortable of shoes to be walking around in to begin with. Not to mention having to get very thick socks that roll all the way up to your knees. </strong></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p class="has-text-align-center">Great way to make this a little bit more enjoyable and pleasurable, is to get socks that have plenty of cushioning and her overall very comfortable to wear.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p class="has-text-align-center">You don’t want socks that are uncomfortable and are always falling down, so just make sure to grab some very high-quality thick, and comfortable types of socks to wear with your cowboy boots.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p class="has-text-align-center">Another thing to consider when you’re deciding on whether or not to wear socks while wearing boots, is to grab some socks that fit you well enough. That means get socks that are somewhat tight but not too uncomfortable. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p class="has-text-align-center">This will just help the socks stay in place and ensure that you never have to you always roll up your pants and reapply the socks back up to your knees. I’ve done that many times and it’s frankly very annoying.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>About</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/about/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/about/</id>

        <updated>2022-02-17T17:17:34-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                     A Native Texan who loves to travel, go on hikes, spend time with his dog Mara, and much much more! 
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:kadence/rowlayout {"uniqueID":"_e40dfb-52","columns":1,"colLayout":"equal","maxWidth":800,"topPadding":80,"bottomPadding":80} --></p>
<div class="wp-block-kadence-rowlayout alignnone">
<div id="kt-layout-id_e40dfb-52" class="kt-row-layout-inner kt-layout-id_e40dfb-52">
<div class="kt-row-column-wrap kt-has-1-columns kt-gutter-default kt-v-gutter-default kt-row-valign-top kt-row-layout-equal kt-tab-layout-inherit kt-m-colapse-left-to-right kt-mobile-layout-row">
<p><!-- wp:kadence/column {"uniqueID":"_31660e-04"} --></p>
<div class="wp-block-kadence-column inner-column-1 kadence-column_31660e-04">
<div class="kt-inside-inner-col">
<p><!-- wp:kadence/advancedheading {"uniqueID":"_d3e0ec-a8","align":"center","size":36,"fontWeight":"500"} --></p>
<h2 class="kt-adv-heading_d3e0ec-a8 wp-block-kadence-advancedheading" data-kb-block="kb-adv-heading_d3e0ec-a8">Texas Walkabout</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:kadence/advancedheading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center","textColor":"theme-palette6"} --></p>
<p class="has-text-align-center has-theme-palette-6-color has-text-color">A Native Texan who loves to travel, go on hikes, spend time with his dog Mara, and much much more!</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:kadence/advancedgallery {"uniqueID":"_69a216-e2","columns":[2,2,2,2,1,1],"thumbSize":"full","ids":["1195",1204],"type":"tiles","imageRatio":"inherit","gutter":[24,"",""]} --></p>
<div class="wp-block-kadence-advancedgallery kb-gallery-wrap-id-_69a216-e2">
<div class="kadence-blocks-gallery-item-inner">
<figure class="kb-gallery-figure kadence-blocks-gallery-item-hide-caption">
<div class="kb-gal-image-radius">
<div class="kb-gallery-image-contain"><figure class="wp-image-1195 skip-lazy"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/1/IMG_1916-scaled.jpeg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_1916-scaled-xs.jpeg 300w ,https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_1916-scaled-sm.jpeg 480w ,https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_1916-scaled-md.jpeg 768w ,https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_1916-scaled-lg.jpeg 1024w ,https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_1916-scaled-xl.jpeg 1360w ,https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_1916-scaled-2xl.jpeg 1600w"  alt="" width="2560" height="1920" data-full-image="https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/1/IMG_1916-scaled.jpeg" data-light-image="https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/1/IMG_1916-scaled.jpeg" data-id="1195" data-link="http://www.texaswalkabout.com/about-2/img_1916/"></figure></div>
</div>
</figure>
</div>
<br>
<div class="kadence-blocks-gallery-item-inner">
<figure class="kb-gallery-figure kadence-blocks-gallery-item-hide-caption">
<div class="kb-gal-image-radius">
<div class="kb-gallery-image-contain"><figure class="wp-image-1204 skip-lazy"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/1/IMG_2303.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_2303-xs.jpg 300w ,https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_2303-sm.jpg 480w ,https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_2303-md.jpg 768w ,https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_2303-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_2303-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_2303-2xl.jpg 1600w"  alt="" width="960" height="1792" data-full-image="https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/1/IMG_2303.jpg" data-light-image="https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/1/IMG_2303.jpg" data-id="1204" data-link="http://www.texaswalkabout.com/about-2/img_2303/"></figure></div>
</div>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<p><!-- /wp:kadence/advancedgallery --></p>
</div>
</div>
<p><!-- /wp:kadence/column --></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p><!-- /wp:kadence/rowlayout --></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
