<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Texas Walkabout</title>
    <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com" />
    <updated>2022-03-29T18:59:54-05:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://texaswalkabout.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Why do surgeons wear cowboy boots? (Explained)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/why-do-surgeons-wear-cowboy-boots/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/why-do-surgeons-wear-cowboy-boots/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-29T18:59:54-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    You’ve seen them around. That slick leather-made footwear. Cowboy boots are worn by all kinds of people everywhere. Yet, do some professions allow them? What if that person were a surgeon? In this article, we’ll discuss the answer to that question and more! When your&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>You’ve seen them around. That slick leather-made footwear. Cowboy boots are worn by all kinds of people everywhere. Yet, do some professions allow them? What if that person were a surgeon? In this article, we’ll discuss the answer to that question and more!</p>
<hr>
<h2><strong>Why do surgeons wear cowboy boots? Some say they’re highly functional.</strong></h2>
<p>When your job requires you to stand for hours on end, you’ll need some serious support for your feet. One <a href="https://www.nbcdfw.com/news/local/do-your-feet-a-favor-wear-cowboy-boots/273223/">surgeon</a> claims that his cowboy boots give him “a built-in heel lift” that reduces stress on his Achilles tendon. Not only that, cowboy boots can also give surgeons overall “solid support” because of rigid metal shanks within the soles.</p>
<p>In this case, surgeons need footwear that won’t cause them problems later on in the day. It’s also recommended that any surgeon shopping for cowboy boots get a pair that has <a href="https://www.nbcdfw.com/news/local/do-your-feet-a-favor-wear-cowboy-boots/273223/">more room in the toe box</a> like a rounded or square toe.</p>
<p>The material that cowboy boots are made of can also factor in to the wearer’s overall comfortability. Some materials like ostrich leather are more “forgiving” towards those who suffer from bunions.</p>
<hr>
<h2><strong>Do doctors wear cowboy boots? Yes they do. </strong></h2>
<p>One doctor describes how his pair of cowboy boots <a href="https://www.quora.com/Can-surgeons-wear-any-shoes">protect his feet</a> from all the gore and guts that comes with surgery. Most surgeons are required to wear something that is waterproof so they don’t risk contaminating their feet with someone else’s bodily fluids.</p>
<p>Whereas not exactly waterproof, cowboy boots are highly <a href="https://horseracingsense.com/cowboy-boots-waterproof-leather-snow/">water resistant</a> and can take a bit of punishment. However, it's not recommended that the wearer expose the boots to things like snow and excessive moisture too often, lest the leather on the boots crack and dry.</p>
<p>With that being said, there are certain <a href="https://www.amazon.ca/s?k=mink+oil+for+leather&amp;linkCode=gs3&amp;linkId=14aca1efebe9d0f444342d27cd2da62a&amp;tag=horseracing04-20&amp;ref=as_li_ss_tl">products</a> one can get to make cowboy boots even more water resistant. They don’t seem that expensive either, as anyone wanting to strengthen their footwear can buy things like mink oil for just over $10.</p>
<p>For the most part, surgeons and other kinds of medical doctors can wear any kind of footwear they please, as long as they follow proper sterile procedures. When delivering babies, for example, doctors are required to slip on <a href="https://www.quora.com/Can-surgeons-wear-any-shoes">disposable waterproof boots</a> over whatever shoes or boots they’re wearing at the time.</p>
<hr>
<h2><strong>What is the purpose of wearing cowboy boots? Function <em>and</em> style. </strong></h2>
<p>Ever since the late 1800s, cowboy boots have been used extensively by common folk. One of the <a href="https://stageswest.com/blog/benefits-of-wearing-cowboy-boots/">earliest innovations</a> of the cowboy boots, the toe shape, was made in such a way that it easily allows the wearer to get boots in and out of stirrups.</p>
<p>And that gift keeps on giving. The cowboy boot design also allows the wearer to remain firm within the stirrups while riding a horse. Also, the tough leather cowboy boots are made to protect the wearer from bushes, cacti, thorns, branches, and snakes!</p>
<p>Even today, cowboy boots are used for the same purposes. They’re also quite comfortable to wear, especially if the wearer gets them properly fitted. And seeing how they don’t use laces, anyone can slip them on and off at their leisure, as well as keep them on for long periods of time without the worry of any laces coming undone.</p>
<hr>
<h2><strong>What shoes do surgeons wear during surgery? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>They can wear just about anything they want. However, some shoes serve their purposes better than others.</strong></p>
<p>As we’ve established already, cowboy boots may not be the best kind of footwear for surgeons due to the need for waterproofing around their feet. Shoes such as <a href="https://testprepnerds.com/mcat/best-shoes-surgeons/">Crocs</a> are preferred for the operating room due to their slip resistance.</p>
<p>And like cowboy boots, doctors who do surgery often prefer something that they can easily slip on and off, like a pair of clogs, for example. Whereas certain kinds of shoes (with laces) are worn by surgeons as well, it’s much more convenient to slip your feet in and forget them before an important job.</p>
<p>Another feature surgeons look out for is <a href="https://testprepnerds.com/mcat/best-shoes-surgeons/">protection</a> against sharp objects, cold, and impact injuries to their feet. Some OR rooms can be uncomfortably chilly, and standing still in this environment can sap away all the feet warmth.</p>
<hr>
<h2><strong>Are cowboy boots comfortable to wear for long periods of time? They can be. </strong></h2>
<p>This is where a potential owner of cowboy boots should look out for function over style. This is because shopping for <a href="https://horseracingsense.com/are-cowboy-boots-comfortable/">style alone</a> can leave the wearer disappointed (and possibly injured!). The key here is, take your time when browsing around for this iconic kind of footwear. Chances are that you’ll have your new boots for a long time to come. Cowboy boots, if properly taken care of, can last for <a href="https://stageswest.com/blog/benefits-of-wearing-cowboy-boots/">years on end</a>.</p>
<p>Even if you find the right pair for you, you’ll still need to <a href="https://horseracingsense.com/how-break-in-ariat-leather-cowboy-boots/">break into them</a> so that they mold to the shape of your feet. This process is made much easier when you obtain a pair that actually fits. One way to speed up the process even further is using <a href="https://horseracingsense.com/how-break-in-ariat-leather-cowboy-boots/">steam</a> to soften the leather, making it relaxed enough to mold over a short period of time.</p>
<hr>
<h2><strong>Final Thoughts</strong></h2>
<p>Keep in mind that even though surgeons like to wear cowboy boots at work, you don’t need to be a medical doctor to enjoy their full benefits. As we’ve surmised, cowboy boots are tough, comfortable, and stylish enough for just about any job out there.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Suede vs leather cowboy boots (Explained)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/suede-vs-leather-cowboy-boots/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/suede-vs-leather-cowboy-boots/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-27T11:49:16-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Suede vs leather cowboy boots So you’re looking into getting a fresh pair of stylish cowboy boots. However, the more you search online and in local stores, you find that there’s so much to choose from! After many hard hours of researching, you narrow your&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h2 class="p1">Suede vs leather cowboy boots</h2>
<p class="p1">So you’re looking into getting a fresh pair of stylish cowboy boots. However, the more you search online and in local stores, you find that there’s so much to choose from! After many hard hours of researching, you narrow your choices down to two kinds of material: suede and leather. Yet, now the question remains, which do you choose? Fear not, because in this article, we’ll compare the two materials in detail, and which pair (or pairs) of cowboy boots will work for your lifestyle.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p1"><strong>Are suede boots more comfortable? Definitely.</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">First, we need to understand what suede and leather <i>are,</i> respectively. Essentially, the two materials come from the <a href="https://www.fromtheguestroom.com/suede-vs-leather-cowboy-boots/"><span class="s1">same origin</span></a>, meaning suede is the inner layer of the animal skin, while leather composes the outer. However, despite them being made from the same cloth (quite literally), there are still some stark differences between the two. A major one is comfort.</p>
<p class="p1">Suede itself tends to be very smooth to the touch, up to the point of being called “buttery” in appearance. This material is well-known for being highly skin friendly. Its silky smooth surface will satisfy just about any person who needs something non-abrasive for their footwear needs. If you want to avoid breaking into your new pair of boots, go with suede over leather.</p>
<p class="p1">Leather is typically tougher and harder to get used to at first. As it’s made from the outer part of the animal skin, it features a hardy nature that repels the elements such as rain and cold. If you spend a lot of time outdoors and need a tough pair of boots to do your activities (hiking, working outdoors, ranching, etc.), pick up a pair of tough leather cowboy boots over suede. They might be a bit less comfortable, but at least your feet will be better protected.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p1"><strong>Are suede boots dressier than leather? It depends what your definition of “dressy” is.</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">Suede, in this case, has a “furry” surface that prevents certain kinds of decoration or embroidery from sticking to it. If you want your cowboy boots to have elaborate designs that you can show off to the world, stick with the leather variety.</p>
<p class="p1">However, suede can still have decorations imprinted on it, but it would have to be through burning methods or lasers. This makes your choices of color and decoration much more limited, as opposed to leather.</p>
<p class="p1">If your definition of dressy lies with a more comfortable or even “buttery” look, then stick with suede. This appearance has been known to work well with indoor gatherings.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p1"><strong>How do you protect suede cowboy boots?</strong> <strong>You’ll need a specific coating.</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">Before getting into the meat and potatoes of the subject, keep in mind that you’ll need to give your suede cowboy boots a <a href="https://www.ariat.com/al/how-to-clean-suede-boots"><span class="s1">thorough cleaning</span></a> first. For all minor blemishes, apply some water and a soft brush (toothbrush, for example). For anything tougher than that, use either white vinegar or a pencil eraser.</p>
<p class="p1">For further protection, you’ll need to apply a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zI0YBGgSFR8"><span class="s1">suede protector</span></a>. These can be picked up at your local department stores such as Walmart. Simply follow the directions on the can to give your suede boots the protection they need.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p1"><strong>Which is better, suede or leather? It vastly depends what you need them for.</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">There is no one answer to this question. Which cowboy boot material is better all depends on <i>why</i> you want to wear them. Want to show off your hot new boots at a country music concert? Go with leather cowboy boots. Anything involving walking around in wet, harsh environments requires tough materials. That, or if your job needs you to be outdoors a lot. Leather is also quite <a href="https://www.fromtheguestroom.com/suede-vs-leather-cowboy-boots/"><span class="s1">waterproof</span></a>.</p>
<p class="p1">Need something more casual and comfortable? Pick suede instead. Boots made with suede leather are also more <a href="https://www.fromtheguestroom.com/suede-vs-leather-cowboy-boots/"><span class="s1">breathable</span></a>, meaning your feet won’t get too sweaty over time. This is especially nice to have for hot weather.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p1"><strong>Which material is better for over-the-knee cowboy boots? Again, the answer lies in what your footwear needs are.</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">Over-the-knee cowboy boots don’t differ much from their shorter cousins, aside from the fact that their shafts extend above the knee. Which material you pick is dependent on where you’ll go, and what you’ll walk on (or in).</p>
<p class="p1">There are some <a href="https://www.buzzfeed.com/brittany_gibson/best-over-the-knee-boots"><span class="s1">positive</span></a> reviews out there that advocate both leather and suede, but what’s best for <i>you</i> might be different from all those satisfied customers out there. If you don’t mind breaking into your boots and want them to last for <a href="https://www.fromtheguestroom.com/suede-vs-leather-cowboy-boots/"><span class="s1">years on end</span></a>, choose leather above all. If you don’t like the idea of your boots chaffing your skin every time you go for a long walk, pick suede.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p1"><strong>Which is better for winter, suede or leather? Leather.</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">Despite them lacking in the comfort department, leather cowboy boots will <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/celiashatzman/2015/01/28/6-ways-to-avoid-ruining-your-boots-this-winter/?sh=3157631388f7"><span class="s1">protect</span></a> you from snow and ice. Leather will insulate your feet better from wet and cold than suede ever can.</p>
<p class="p1">Due to its breathability, suede will instead absorb moisture so much that you run the risk of getting wet feet. Even though wearing a pair of suede cowboy boots is comfortable, they won’t fare so well during the winter season.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p1"><strong>Final Thoughts</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">All in all, which material works best for you depends on multiple factors, perhaps even some ones that weren’t covered in this article! Other things like arch support, toe-width, ankle support, and even skin conditions might also need to be considered.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Wearing cowboy boots to school (Should you do it?)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/wearing-cowboy-boots-to-school/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/wearing-cowboy-boots-to-school/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-27T11:47:56-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    As a student, you might be starting off the school year soon, or you’re already deep into your courses. You’d like to try wearing cowboy boots to your classes, but aren’t sure if that’s a good idea. Are they practical, or are they even in&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p class="p1">As a student, you might be starting off the school year soon, or you’re already deep into your courses. You’d like to try wearing cowboy boots to your classes, but aren’t sure if that’s a good idea. Are they practical, or are they even in <i>style</i>? To give students a boost of confidence, no matter what kind of school they go to (high school, college, university, whatever!) we’ll discuss some cowboy boot facts and how you can pull the look off.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p1"><strong>How do you wear cowboy boots without looking country? It depends on what <i>else</i> you wear with them.</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">Putting on the first pair of cowboy boots you’ve ever worn won’t immediately make you look like you just came out of a country music concert (but if that’s your thing, go for it!). Pulling off a certain look can also mean what <a href="https://rmkshoes.com/wear-cowboy-boots-without-looking-country/"><span class="s1">other kinds of clothes</span></a> you wear with your boots as well. You need not dash over to the mall for anything new, either. Pieces of clothing such as t-shirts or even <a href="https://rmkshoes.com/wear-cowboy-boots-without-looking-country/"><span class="s1">khakis</span></a> can go nicely with cowboy boots.</p>
<p class="p1">Another good piece of advice is to wear them with <a href="https://rmkshoes.com/wear-cowboy-boots-without-looking-country/"><span class="s1">confidence</span></a>. It’s not so much what you wear, but a lot more about <i>how</i>.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p1"><strong>Can you wear boots to school? If you want!</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">As long as your institution <a href="https://www.quora.com/Can-I-wear-long-boots-to-school"><span class="s1">dress code</span></a> allows it, go ahead! The question you should be asking yourself is not <i>can</i> you, but <i>will</i> you?</p>
<p class="p1">Just to be absolutely sure though, check your school rules. If you don’t notice anything mentioning that “cowboy boots” specifically aren’t allowed in any way, shape or manner, then it should be okay to bring them with you.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p1"><strong>Are cowboy boots in style? Yep!</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">When trying to wear them with “style,” pick a combination of clothes that feels both comfortable and awesome to you. Part of achieving the “how” of wearing any outfit includes fabric that doesn’t bother your skin, and a look that looks good to <i>you</i> in the mirror.</p>
<p class="p1">If you don’t have a good idea despite trial and error, you might find your style in any of these 2022 guides both for <a href="https://bootspy.com/what-do-cowboy-boots-say-about-a-man/"><span class="s1">men</span></a> and <a href="https://www.purewow.com/fashion/how-to-wear-cowboy-boots"><span class="s1">women</span></a>. These are what’s considered most popular currently, and fashion trends come and go, but cowboy boots seem to stand the test of time.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p1"><strong>Can you wear cowboy boots casually? By wearing casual things.</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">No real rocket science for this one, just pick a <a href="https://www.ariat.com/al/what-to-wear-with-cowboy-boots"><span class="s1">common piece of clothing</span></a> to go along with your chosen pair of cowboy boots. Even wearing a t-shirt and jean combo can complement the footwear.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p1"><strong>Can you wear cowboy boots every day? Why not?</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">As we’ve established, cowboy boots are still comfortable and appropriate for just about any place you go. Those who wear cowboy boots seven days a week like to keep <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/cowboyboots/comments/8ema4r/how_many_of_you_wear_your_boots_everyday/"><span class="s1">an extra pair</span></a> at all times so they can cycle through to prevent too much wear and tear.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p1"><strong>Can you wear cowboy boots anywhere? Sure can!</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">Going a bit more in-depth, the answer to wearing anything in any environment lies strongly in the <a href="https://www.wikihow.com/Wear-Cowboy-Boots"><span class="s1">how</span></a>. Be warned, though, that going <i>too</i> country might send the wrong message (unless that’s your intent). Avoiding clothing that contrasts too differently with each other might be a good idea as well.</p>
<p class="p1">What also helps, again, is maintaining your own confidence. First learn to feel comfortable, then feel good about your choice of outfit, enter the public sphere.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p1"><strong>Is it weird to wear cowboy boots in the summer? No, not really.</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">Considering how tough leather <a href="https://durabilitymatters.com/how-long-does-real-leather-last/"><span class="s1">is</span></a>, it can be used for just about any outdoor weather. If you grab the right kind of pair, such as a <a href="https://harrysboots.com/how-to-wear-cowboy-boots-in-summer/"><span class="s1">sandal replacement</span></a> or even a work boot, you’ll have both comfort <i>and</i> style on your side.</p>
<p class="p1">That is, of course, if you choose to go with something that stands out, especially the “western” look, it might not be appropriate for all scenarios. Work boots should be worn at work and hardly anywhere else, for example. Don’t wear short and highly breathable cowboy boots when it’s raining outside, as another example.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p1"><strong>Bonus content: other things to consider.</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">It might be tempting, but <a href="https://rmkshoes.com/wear-cowboy-boots-without-looking-country/"><span class="s1">avoid</span></a> tucking your jeans into those wide cowboy boots. This is usually done for wandering through thick and dangerous terrain or riding a horse, and can ruin your pant leggings through multiple wrinkles.</p>
<p class="p1">Also, go with a size that simply <i>feels</i> comfortable to walk in. You’re going to wear cowboy boots like shoes for hours on end, so finding the pair that feels right will increase your confidence levels as well. To add to that, keep in mind that so, so many <a href="https://www.wikihow.com/Wear-Cowboy-Boots"><span class="s1">styles</span></a> of cowboy boots exist out there. Aim to feel <i>and</i> look great (in the mirror first, of course).</p>
<p class="p1">Again, confidence, confidence, <i>confidence.</i> As we’ve covered <a href="https://rmkshoes.com/wear-cowboy-boots-without-looking-country/"><span class="s1">before</span></a>, in addition to finding some comfortable footwear, keep a straight posture and walk like you know where you’re going.</p>
<p class="p1">Confidence in itself will usually surface the more you practice it, just like any skill. When you go to the gym, you lift weights, tearing muscle tissue, and your body repairs any damage to make it stronger and larger over time (eat good food if you decide to do this!). The same applies for non-physical skills, such as mental.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p1"><strong>Final thoughts</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">All in all, pick what you want. Cowboy boots are a fun thing to try, not a mandatory one.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Why are my cowboy boots so loud? (Explained)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/why-are-my-cowboy-boots-so-loud/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/why-are-my-cowboy-boots-so-loud/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-27T11:46:22-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    If you’re asking why your cowboy boots are loud, you are not alone. An unfortunate feature of cowboy boots sometimes is announcing the wearer’s entrance into a room through loud squeaking. At first, this sound might not bother you (or those around you) too much.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p class="p1">If you’re asking why your cowboy boots are loud, you are not alone. An unfortunate feature of cowboy boots sometimes is announcing the wearer’s entrance into a room through loud squeaking. At first, this sound might not bother you (or those around you) too much. However, this sound can wear on even the most patient western boot wearer.</p>
<p class="p1">Luckily for you, we have the answer for why cowboy boots might be loud and how to fix them. To summarize, cowboy boots are loud sometimes because the soles have become unattached. If this is not the case, it might be because the pair of cowboy boots is new; the outsoles have become tacky and stick to the floor, making a sound as they come unstuck; the leather is old or stiff, causing it to be loud as it moves; or perhaps the problem is inside the boot, related to the insoles.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p2"><strong>Why are my cowboy boots so loud?</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">As we mentioned earlier, cowboy boots can seem oddly loud for a variety of reasons.</p>
<p class="p1">The main reasons for loud cowboy boots that thud on the ground could either be that your cowboy boots are a tad loose, which makes them hit the ground at a different rate than your feet. Also, most cowboy boots have a little bit of a heel, so the heel might make a sound that is impossible to avoid unless you sand down the heel, which could ruin the shoe.</p>
<p class="p1">Cowboy boots could be squeaking due to a whole host of causes. The chief reasons behind squeaky cowboy boots include unattached outer or inner soles. Sometimes the bottom of the cowboy boots has gotten gummy from coming into contact with a sticky substance and they squeak as they lift from the floor. New, old or inflexible leather will also make a squeaking sound. Sometimes the cowboy boots squeak because they have come in contact with water either through the rain or through traipsing through muddy terrain. This can cause the shoes to squeak until they get cleaned off or dry naturally.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p2"><strong>How do you make your cowboy boots quieter?</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">This really depends on the source of the annoyingly loud sound and the type of sound. If the heels of cowboy boots are clacking loudly and disturbing those around you, there are not many solutions to this other than trying to tread more lightly and mindfully. Taking shorter, lighter strides might fix this issue.</p>
<p class="p1">If the issue is related to squeaking, the solution will depend entirely on the source of the problem. For boots that squeak because they are tacky on the bottom, a simple inspection of the bottom of the shoe and wiping it down with a wet cloth should solve the problem. They may still squeak for a little bit as they dry, so you can speed up the quieting-down process by drying them with a clean, dry cloth after wiping them down. If the issue is an unattached sole, using an appropriate adhesive recommended by a leather specialist should fix the loud noise issue. When the problem seems to be related to the soles coming in contact with water, drying them off with a clean dry cloth should remedy the issue.</p>
<p class="p1">Finally, if the issue seems to be the condition of the leather such as dryness or stiffness or aging, using a leather conditioner might help the boots make less noise. However, it is best to consult with a leather specialist or do your research before applying any old leather product to your boots. If you apply an inappropriate solution to the leather, it could ruin it or make it worse.</p>
<p class="p1">If your boots are still loud after a thorough examination and application of whatever seems to be the most appropriate course of action, you may want to consult with other cowboy boot enthusiasts to see if they have suggestions to solve the issue.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p2"><strong>Are cowboy boots supposed to be loud?</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">Yes and no.</p>
<p class="p1">Since cowboy boots usually have a heel and are sometimes a heavy-weighted shoe to help them hold up to ranch-related tasks for years, they can be louder than lighter footwear such as tennis shoes or flat sandals. However, squeaking is a sound that might indicate that something is wrong with your boots. At the very least, squeaking is an issue that can usually be fixed with a little investigation and some work.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p2"><strong>What does it mean if cowboy boots are loud?</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">If your cowboy boots are squeaking, it could mean that there is an issue with the soles, something is sticking to the bottom of the shoe, the leather quality is old or stiffening up, or it could mean that the insoles have absorbed some water that needs drying out.</p>
<p class="p1">Depending on how loud your cowboy boots are or what type of loud sound they are making, it could mean that they are just being normal cowboy boots. Some clacking of the heels is a totally normal sound to hear coming from the heels of cowboy boots.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p2"><strong>Final thoughts</strong></h2>
<p class="p1"><strong>In short, cowboy boots can be loud for many different reasons. It all comes down to the individual pair of boots. Whether your boots are heavy, sticky, wet, disconnecting from their soles, relatively new, or beginning to show their age or dryness levels, squeaking sounds are not exactly normal for cowboy boots.</strong></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Ariat boots vs double h (Explained)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/ariat-boots-vs-double-h/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/ariat-boots-vs-double-h/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-27T11:45:20-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Ariat boots vs double h Ariat boots versus double h boots; both well-known brands of cowboy boots. Is one better than the other? We will provide you with all the information to allow you to make that decision on your own accord. Please read this&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h2 class="p1">Ariat boots vs double h</h2>
<p class="p2"> </p>
<p class="p1"><strong>Ariat boots versus double h boots; both well-known brands of cowboy boots. Is one better than the other? We will provide you with all the information to allow you to make that decision on your own accord. Please read this article all the way until the end!</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p1"><strong>What are double h cowboy boots?</strong></h2>
<p class="p1"><strong>Over the past 50 years, this boot company has crafted the most intricately-styled western cowboy boots in the industry. They are primarily aimed at the new breed of cowboy we see in the world today.</strong></p>
<p class="p1">The name Double-H Boots comes from its long heritage in association with H.H. Brown. The manufacturing and warehouse space's vast facility is located in Martinsburg, Pennsylvania.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p1"><strong>What are Ariat boots?</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">The name itself is a shortened version of Secretarial, the world-famous race horse. The cowboy boots they make are the boot equivalent of that fame. Ariat designs classic-styled boots for men and women of all ages. Each pair is a work of art.</p>
<p class="p1"><strong>Ariat boots go through a rigorous construction process in the name of great quality. They are strictly tested before they ever reach a store or website. All the customer needs to do is see and feel a pair to appreciate the splendor of wearing these boots.</strong></p>
<p class="p1"> </p>
<h2 class="p1"><strong>Ariat boots vs double h where are they made?</strong></h2>
<p class="p1"><strong>As we discussed earlier, Double H boots are made right here in the United States in the heart of Pennsylvania. </strong>The official websites showcase footwear with impeccable technology and incredible safety and comfort features.</p>
<p class="p1">Ariat in its entirety is officially Ariat International. It is an extremely American apparel, accessories, and especially a footwear brand. <strong>The facility is housed in Union City, California.</strong> It should be mentioned that both brands of boots are the highest quality a customer can get.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p1"><strong>Ariat boots vs double h price?</strong></h2>
<p class="p1"><strong>Double H boots tend to range from the low 100s to around $300. </strong>Most of them are somewhere in the middle of those two figures. They take into consideration the craftsmanship in addition to the quality of the leather. When you buy a pair of Double H boots, you know they are superb and will last for decades.</p>
<p class="p1">Ariat cowboy and western boots average slightly lower in price than the Double H. But make no mistake about it, the quality of their boots is every bit as fantastic. From the wide array of styles to the availability of these boots to anybody who wants a pair, there is no denying Ariats are also incredible boots.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p1"><strong>Ariat boots vs double h waterproof factor</strong></h2>
<p class="p1"><strong>Double H boots can come in models that are waterproof. </strong>They can stand up to water, sleet, snow, and ice; of course, provided they are properly cared for after exposure to these elements. These versatile boots are also resistant to punctures in their soles as well as to the hazard of slipping.</p>
<p class="p1">To those people who claim there are no such things as waterproof boots, we would like to introduce them to Ariat! They make several models of boots that meet this special criteria. They can be found in stores in addition to online sources. And yes, this DOES include cowboy and western boots!</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p1"><strong>Ariat boots vs double h the comfortability factor</strong></h2>
<p class="p1"><strong>Despite the rugged nature of Double H cowboy boots, they are extremely comfortable to wear and quite functional.</strong> They routinely feature a leather lining that combats moisture and provides breathability to your feet. Try on each pair until you find one with that perfect fit for your feet, and they will be so comfortable, you will never want to remove them.</p>
<p class="p1">The Ariat boots are every bit as comfortable as the Double H and more, as they hold up well when walking a lot. These boots are especially great on rugged terrain as long as you make the effort to properly clean them afterwards.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="p1"><strong>Final Thoughts</strong></h2>
<p class="p1"><strong>Whichever brand of boots you choose, you are getting a classy style of boot. There are hundreds of models, each serving a variety of purposes. Ariat boots and Double H boots are equal in quality and durability. Best of all, they all look mighty fine when you wear them. Either brand you select will be a marvelous choice. Wear your boots proudly and enjoy them!</strong></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Why Are Cowboy Boots so Slippery?  (Explained)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/why-are-cowboy-boots-so-slippery/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/why-are-cowboy-boots-so-slippery/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-27T11:43:50-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    When cowboy boots were popularized in the 1800s, virtually all boots had leather soles. Today, there are many different styles of boots on the market, including boots with rubber soles. While both types of boots have their advantages, leather soles don't provide a lot of&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p class="p1">When cowboy boots were popularized in the 1800s, virtually all boots had leather soles. Today, there are many different styles of boots on the market, including boots with rubber soles.</p>
<p class="p1">While both types of boots have their advantages, leather soles don't provide a lot of grip. If you've noticed that your boots seem to be slippery, you don't have to get used to it. There are ways to add traction to the soles of your boots so that you can wear them without slipping.</p>
<h2 class="p2"><strong>Why Are Cowboy Boots so Slippery?</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">Cowboy boots aren't always slippery, but your boots may not have much traction if they have leather outsoles. Even when leather soles are designed to be slip-resistant, the smooth texture of the soles keeps them from gripping the surface that you're walking across.</p>
<p class="p1">Rubber soles are designed to produce friction as you walk. Thanks to this, cowboy boots with rubber soles usually aren't that slippery. With that said, if you've already invested in a pair of boots with leather soles, you don't have to keep slipping and sliding as you walk. There are steps you can take that will give your boots a little more grip.</p>
<h2 class="p2"><strong>How Do I Make My Cowboy Boots Less Slippery?</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">Wearing your cowboy boots regularly will scuff the soles of the shoes, giving you more traction. If you're looking for a quicker solution to this issue, you could scuff the soles yourself using an abrasive material, like sandpaper. You could also try adding grip pads to the bottom of your soles.</p>
<p class="p1">Later down the road, when you're ready to re-sole your boots, you could also ask the cobbler to replace your old leather sole with a new rubber sole. You could even opt for a hybrid sole, which combines leather and rubber. High-quality cowboy boots are designed to last for years, and even if you're not completely satisfied with your boots, there are plenty of ways to improve them.</p>
<h2 class="p2"><strong>Are Cowboy Boots Supposed to Slip?</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">Cowboy boots were originally designed for workers that ride horses. Wearing boots with slippery leather soles made it easier to mount and dismount horses. Rubber soles, which provide more traction, can easily get stuck on stirrups when riding.</p>
<p class="p1">Wearing boots with very smooth soles can also be an advantage while line dancing. If you're working, it might be frustrating when your feet slide across the floor as you move. When you're dancing, however, smooth soles can make it easier to complete steps. In fact, some line dancers don't wear their boots outside so that the soles will stay as smooth as possible.</p>
<p class="p1">Even though people from all walks of life wear cowboy boots today, there are still advantages to wearing boots with slippery leather soles. Leather is comfortable, breathable, and naturally conforms to the shape of your foot. If you don't need footwear with extra traction, leather-soled boots can be a terrific option.</p>
<h2 class="p2"><strong>How Do You Put Traction on Cowboy Boots?</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">Cowboy boots with leather soles will naturally become more slip-resistant over time, especially if you wear them on rough surfaces like concrete. You can also scuff up the soles of your boots yourself with sandpaper or a nail file, but you should take care not to damage the shoes in the process.</p>
<p class="p1">If you're looking for a safer way to get the grip that you need, the best thing you can do is take your boots to a cobbler. A cobbler can apply a thin grip finish to the soles of your boots, instantly giving you more traction. If you'd prefer to do things yourself, there are also rubber grips that you can add to your soles at home.</p>
<h2 class="p2"><strong>Final Thoughts</strong></h2>
<p class="p1">Cowboy boots aren't always slippery, but boots with smooth leather soles might not provide enough traction for the average user. If you're in the market for a pair of cowboy boots, and you want something slip-resistant, you should look for rubber-soled boots that have great grip.</p>
<p class="p1">If you have cowboy boots with leather soles, and you want to make them less slippery, you have plenty of options. Leather soles may not provide the traction that rubber soles do, but you can get more grip by scuffing up your soles or applying a stick-on grip. You don't necessarily have to replace your cowboy boots if you're not happy with them. There are plenty of ways to adapt your boots to your needs.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Why do texans wear cowboy boots? (Explained)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/why-do-texans-wear-cowboy-boots/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/why-do-texans-wear-cowboy-boots/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-23T17:39:57-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Cowboy boots are a staple of the Texas aesthetic of deserts and cattle ranches. Cowboy boots date back to the 16th century when they functioned for riding horses and farming needs. Texans wore cowboy boots for riding horses, cattle drives, and other ranch work. The&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><strong>Cowboy boots are a staple of the Texas aesthetic of deserts and cattle ranches. Cowboy boots date back to the 16th century when they functioned for riding horses and farming needs. Texans wore cowboy boots for riding horses, cattle drives, and other ranch work. </strong></p>
<p>The cowboy boot has a heel that keeps the shoe in a stirrup for stability. The end of the boot is round at the toe for comfort. Their sturdy build and heels make them a perfect match for all cowboy needs.</p>
<p>Cowboy boots' functionality and purpose can make them quite dirty. People started owning two different types of boots. Texans owned a pair for their work and ranch needs and a flashy pair to pair with their street style. Fashionable cowboy boots led to different styles and colors of boots to go with any Texan aesthetic.</p>
<h2>Are Cowboy Boots Popular in Texas?</h2>
<p><strong>Even though life in Texas is no longer an exact Western movie, cowboy boots are still popular. </strong>Texas has changed to adapt to modern life in the U.S., and some cities like Dallas and Austin have become artistic hubs. Even in modern-day Texas, many of the people in the state still wear cowboy boots for fashion and usefulness.</p>
<p>The cowboy boot has been passed down from generation to generation in Texas. Its history is in people's choice of shoes. You can see people wearing all types of cowboy boots in Texas, from different pointed toecaps, colors, to leather.</p>
<p>People of any gender wear cowboy boots. Even though the name is masculine, women and men alike wear cowboy boots. They are versatile and everlasting through the ages and changes of Texas.</p>
<h2>What Was The Purpose of Cowboy Boots?</h2>
<p><strong>Cowboy boots are multifunctional for riding horses, herding cattle, and ranch work.</strong> They have been around for centuries, brought to Texas from Spain.</p>
<p>The original cowboy boot can be dated back to the Spanish Vaqueros. They were cowboys from Spain in the 1500s, the 16th century. When the Spanish came to Mexico and Texas, they herded cattle and rode horses. They left much of their traditions in Texas and Mexico and even spread to other parts of America. Mexican cowboy boots offered different leather skin and colors we see today.</p>
<p>In the 1860s, cowboy boots grew in popularity due to the industrial age. Texans began to wear them for their functionality and fashion.</p>
<h2>Did Cowboys Really Wear Cowboy Boots?</h2>
<p><strong>Cowboys did wear cowboy boots and needed them for their abilities.</strong> From the 1860s to the 1890s, cowboys needed boots for cattle drives and riding horses. The original cowboy boot was not the best for cattle and ranch needs.</p>
<p>A bootmaker in Kansas began designing and building boots that the Texans were requesting. Slimmer, a higher heel, and a rounded toe. By the 1870s, Texans received new and improved cowboy boots just like they had asked for.</p>
<h2>Do All Texans Wear Cowboy Boots?</h2>
<p><strong>In the present day and age, not every Texan wears cowboy boots.</strong> As fashion has changed and urban life has found itself in Texas, not all Texans wear cowboy fashion. Many Texans, however, still do.</p>
<p>Cowboy boots have been brought down from generation to generation in Texas. Many Texans wear them to represent Texas and their home. Other Texans wear them for their use in cattle farming and horse riding or racing.</p>
<h2>What Do Texans Wear?</h2>
<p><strong>Texans wear modern, urban, and western fashion.</strong> Since the state is a mix of cultures of different people from all over the country and world, Texas has become a state with multiple styles mixing in one area.</p>
<p>When it comes to western fashion, Texans usually pair cowboy boots with jeans, a western button-down shirt, and a cowboy hat.</p>
<h2>Final Thoughts</h2>
<p>Like in the western days, cowboy boots are still just as popular in Texas. Even though Texas is more contemporary today, Texans still show their western history through their cowboy aesthetic.</p>
<p><strong>Cowboy boots are versatile in their function. They provide comfort and sturdiness for cowboys on a cattle ranch or horse riding. They are also fashionable and often worn by people who do not involve themselves in western life. Cowboy boots will always have an everlasting impression on Texas fashion.</strong></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to make cowboy boots smell better? (Explained)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/how-to-make-cowboy-boots-smell-better/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/how-to-make-cowboy-boots-smell-better/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-23T15:53:45-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    This is an easier fix than you might think. All you need to do is sprinkle baking soda all over the inside of both boots. Then allow it to sit for at least one night before wearing them. Another option is to use a commercial&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><strong>This is an easier fix than you might think. All you need to do is sprinkle baking soda all over the inside of both boots. Then allow it to sit for at least one night before wearing them. Another option is to use a commercial fabric softener sheet such as Dryel. Tuck one into the bottom of each boot. Let them sit overnight. Then wallah! You have freshened up boots!</strong></p>
<h2>Do leather cowboy boots really stink?</h2>
<p><strong>Sometimes yes. Brand, new leather can have an odor, although it should not be that unpleasant. Most of the time the stink is a result of the wearer's legs sweating inside the boots. This is especially true if he or she has been very active or if it is particularly hot outside.</strong></p>
<p>Foot odor inside your cowboy boots can also come if you have been wearing the boots repeatedly without letting them air out properly. For the best defense against foot odor, allow your cowboy boots to be freshened up for a couple of days.</p>
<h2>Are there any solutions to this?</h2>
<p><strong>Have you been wearing socks inside the boots? You really should be as it tends to negate any unpleasant odors from your feet. If you don't fancy full socks, you can purchase smaller foot pads that cover just the bottoms of your feet. </strong></p>
<p>As far as socks themselves go, you can choose some that are padded. Most department stores carry them. Check with your local Walmart or Target. It is possible that stores where you buy the cowboy boots carry suitable socks or foot pads specifically made to be worn with the boots.</p>
<h2>Cleaning your cowboy boots</h2>
<p><strong>It is important to clean the inside and outside of your boots after each use, particularly if it has been a long use. </strong>We gave you an idea of how to freshen up the insides with baking soda or fabric softener sheets. Did you know that if you never clean the outsides, odors can emanate from there too?</p>
<p>Mud and dirt can build up on the outer parts of the boots, not to mention if you have been cleaning horse or other animal poop while wearing them. Not only will this smell horrible, but it can ruin the boots. Do yourself a favor, clean your boots!</p>
<h2>How to clean the outside of your cowboy boots</h2>
<p><strong>You can buy commercial leather cleaners specifically for cowboy boots. Here are some steps you can take:</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Moisten a rag, sponge, or soft brush with warm water</li>
<li>Gently wipe down the entire boot</li>
<li>While the rag and boots are still damp, apply the leather cleaner</li>
<li>First apply the cleaner to the rag</li>
<li>Then wipe down the boots using a minimal amount of the cleaner</li>
<li>Rinse excess cleaner off the boots with tap water</li>
<li>When finished, allow the boots to air dry naturally</li>
<li>NEVER use a hair dryer as this will damage the boots</li>
<li>If you are in a hurry to wear these boots, you should already own a special boot dryer for such occasions, use it to dry your boots</li>
</ol>
<h2>Can I prevent my boots from smelling?</h2>
<p><strong>It might not be possible to completely prevent this. So many factors are present when cowboy boots begin to smell. However, it should be able to be mitigated and eliminated quickly when they do smell.</strong> How? Keep reading!</p>
<p>By taking our advice for keeping your boots clean, you can lessen the smell that builds up after repeated use. If you have boots you use for dressy occasions, you ought to avoid using them to clean up a mess or when working. Use your alternative pairs of cowboy boots for those chores.</p>
<h2>Getting rid of the smell of new cowboy boots</h2>
<p><strong>Sometimes bacteria or grime has accumulated all over the stitching associated with new, unworn boots. You can take a microfiber cloth or a soft-bristled brush to clean them.</strong></p>
<p>Mix some water with white vinegar and clean the outside of your boots. Be sure to allow them to dry completely before wearing them. This will help you avoid the smell altogether.</p>
<h2>Dealing with your smelly feet!</h2>
<p><strong>Why are we bringing this up? Because it could be a very real reason for the smell coming out of your cowboy boots. Whether you are a man or a woman, some people have incredibly stinky feet.</strong> You know who you are. If it is a chronic thing, you really should see a foot specialist.</p>
<p>If this happens to you after a long day of wearing your boots and is not a medical problem, there are things you can do. There are products available in stores and online that will help reduce the smell. Dr. Scholl's is widely-known for having such products. Other manufacturers probably exist as well. You can always ask a professional about what commercial remedy to buy.</p>
<h2>Final thoughts</h2>
<p><strong>The problem of smelly cowboy boots is not an insurmountable one. There are many solutions. This means you can own a plethora of pairs of them and live happily ever after. This is great news for people who adore wearing cowboy boots. Enjoy them!</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Why do most cowboy boots have no grip soles?  (Explained)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/why-do-cowboy-boots-have-no-grip/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/why-do-cowboy-boots-have-no-grip/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-23T13:17:00-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Why do cowboy boots have no grip? Anyone familiar with cowboy boots knows most makes have no grip. They are extremely slippery. Believe it or not there is a terrific reason for this. We shall explain. Please read all the way through. Because so many&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h1>Why do cowboy boots have no grip?</h1>
<p><strong>Anyone familiar with cowboy boots knows most makes have no grip. They are extremely slippery. Believe it or not there is a terrific reason for this. We shall explain. Please read all the way through.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2>The main reason cowboy boots are designed to be slippery</h2>
<p><strong>Because so many people who wear cowboy boots ride horses, the boots are made slippery on purpose. Horses can be unpredictable. They can rear up or take off running unexpectedly, dragging the rider. Then they can also accidentally fall and land on top of the rider.</strong></p>
<p><strong>If the rider's feet were to get trapped in the stirrups, he or she could get seriously injured or even pass away. Because the soles of the cowboy boots are slippery, they will automatically fall out of the stirrup when the need arises. Thus, the rider does not get trapped on the horse, disaster is avoided. There is your reason cowboy boots are slippery</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2>What about those people who wear cowboy boots that never ride horses?</h2>
<p>There are measures you can take to make your boots less slippery. They include buying pairs that have less slippery soles. These days there are models of cowboy boots available that fit the bill. The rest of this article will focus on these points. Make sure to read it all the way until its end.</p>
<hr>
<h1>Models of cowboy boots with good traction</h1>
<p><strong>See, they do exist! Any of these models of cowboy boots have good traction. </strong>They can be worn by people that do not ride on horses as well as those who wear them on slippery surfaces.</p>
<p>Examples of some slippery surfaces can be pavement that is wet or covered with snow and ice, or a slick department store floor. So, what are some models you can buy for these purposes? Here is a brief list.</p>
<ul>
<li>Tecovas Men's Cowboy Boots</li>
<li>Lucchese Men's Square Toe Boots</li>
<li>Men's Groundbreaker Work Boots</li>
<li>Lucchese Lewis Boots</li>
<li>Lucchese Welted Western Boots</li>
<li>Men's Circuit Patriot Western Boots</li>
<li>Cuero - The Eastwood Men's Cowboy Boots</li>
<li>Dan Post Waterproof Albuquerque Leather Boots</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2>Should you try to put grip on cowboy boots?</h2>
<p>The remainder of this article will focus on those customers who prefer traditional-looking cowboy boots. We shall begin by answering the above question. <strong>That depends on how often you wear them and for what purposes. </strong>If you feel you would benefit from making your boots less slippery, by all means, do it.</p>
<hr>
<h2>How can you accomplish this feat?</h2>
<p><strong>You can start by adding a grainy textured mixture to the soles of your cowboy boots. It is possible to concoct a solution of salt and rubber glue.</strong> Apply this mixture to the bottom of your soles and allow them to dry for about a half hour. Instructions can be found on the Internet, for example on the site where you found this article.</p>
<hr>
<h2>Is there such thing as traction spray for cowboy boots?</h2>
<p><strong>Yes, there are commercial brands of traction spray that you can buy. </strong>You would likely find it at any store where you can buy the boots themselves. Examples are Boot Barn and Cowtown Cowboy Outfitters. Walmart also carries the traction spray.</p>
<p>Traction spray can even be purchased online. Any source from whence you buy cowboy boot products including the ever-reliable Amazon.com and Walmart.com. Grainger.com also carries cowboy boot traction spray. There are scores of options available.</p>
<hr>
<h2>What are some signs your cowboy boots are worn down?</h2>
<p><strong>Keep in mind that, when properly cared for, cowboy boots can last for decades.</strong> The soles of your cowboy boots are constructed to be slippery for the reasons we previously described. Therefore, that is not a sign that the boots are too worn out.</p>
<p>It is possible to step on a nail or piece of glass and accidentally puncture a hole in the soles. You will know if this has happened because rain water or sand from messy pavement will seep in. Other than something like that occurring, you should not need to worry about worn out cowboy boot soles.</p>
<hr>
<h2>Final thoughts</h2>
<p><strong>With the hundreds of models of cowboy boots on the market nowadays, you should have at least one pair for every purpose to wear them. This ought to include a few with rubber soles.</strong> <strong>You would wear these when you do not expect to be on a horse and your local environmental conditions call for them.</strong></p>
<p>Alas, we cannot tell you what to do; we can only suggest. If you insist on buying only cowboy boots with slippery soles, you can follow our advice of how to maneuver in them. Like we said, it is possible to make those boots less slippery. So, go ahead and enjoy the cowboy boots! You deserve them!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How many times can you resole cowboy boots? (Explained) </title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/how-many-times-can-you-resole-cowboy-boots/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/how-many-times-can-you-resole-cowboy-boots/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-23T06:44:39-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    It's normal for cowboy boots to become worn as time goes on. However, there's a good chance that the soles of your boots will wear out before the rest of the shoe does. When this happens, you may want to replace your old sole via&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>It's normal for cowboy boots to become worn as time goes on. However, there's a good chance that the soles of your boots will wear out before the rest of the shoe does. When this happens, you may want to replace your old sole via a process called resoling.</p>
<p>If you resole your boots when they start to wear old, you can put off replacing those boots for a while. Resoling is a cost-effective way to protect your boots and keep them looking and feeling great.</p>
<h2>How Many Times Can You Resole Cowboy Boots?</h2>
<p><strong>The number of times that a pair of cowboy boots can be resoled will vary based on the overall quality of the boots. Typically, boots can be resoled around two or three times. However, if your boots are still in good shape after the third resole, you may be able to resole them a fourth time.</strong></p>
<p>Some manufacturers have limits on the amount of time they'll resole a pair of boots. Thankfully, even if you brush up against these kinds of limits, you'll still have options. Even if you can't have your boots resoled by the manufacturer, you could take them to a cobbler.</p>
<h2>What Does It Mean to Resole a Pair of Cowboy Boots?</h2>
<p><strong>The outer sole of your boots may wear down more quickly than the rest of your boots. Resoling is a process that addresses that issue. When cowboy boots are resoled, the old, worn out sole of a boot will be detached from the shoe, and a new sole will be attached in its place. </strong></p>
<p>Resoling is a way to extend the lifespan of a pair of boots that are mostly in good condition. Instead of paying for a brand-new pair of boots when the sole starts to wear down, you can just replace that old sole with a new one. Resoling can save you money, and it can also give you a way to keep wearing your favorite boots.</p>
<h2>Should You Resole a Pair of Cowboy Boots?</h2>
<p><strong>Resoling is an excellent option for high-quality boots that are mostly in good condition. If you've invested in pricey cowboy boots, you should have your boots resoled as needed. For cheaper, low-quality boots, you may be better off replacing those old boots with something new.</strong></p>
<p>Ultimately, it's up to you to decide if your boots should be resoled. If you're not happy with a pair of cowboy boots, and those boots have started to look worn, this could be an opportunity for you to upgrade to something better. If there are issues with the soles on your favorite cowboy boots, don't hesitate to have those boots resoled!</p>
<h2>Why Would You Have to Resole a Pair of Cowboy Boots?</h2>
<p><strong>Even if you take excellent care of your boots, the soles will eventually wear down. This can cause all kinds of issues. For example, your boots might have uneven soles, or there might be a hole in the sole of one of your boots. If your boots are very worn, the sole might even start to split from the boot!</strong></p>
<p>Cowboy boots are specifically designed to be durable. Most high-quality boots on the market today will have leather soles, which makes them more resistant to the elements. Boots are often made from high-quality leather and are constructed to provide feet with protection and support. However, even the best boots will have worn soles eventually. Resoling is a way to maintain boots so that they can be worn for longer.</p>
<p>Resoling isn't just about appearances. Boots with holes or faulty soles can be a safety hazard. Cowboy boots can be a way to reflect your personal style, but they're also a functional shoe. When you resole your boots, you're ensuring that they're providing your feet with the protection that they need.</p>
<h2>Final Thoughts</h2>
<p>When you wear cowboy boots regularly, the soles of the boots will start to wear down. Not only does this make boots less comfortable, but it can cause serious issues that make the boots unwearable, like holes. Thankfully, the boots can be resoled at least a few times, allowing you to wear them for longer.</p>
<p>Resoling isn't always your best option. When it comes to cheap cowboy boots, you might be better off investing in new boots that are more durable. With that said, resoling can be a fantastic way to save money, prevent further damage, and keep your favorite boots in good condition.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
