<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Texas Walkabout</title>
    <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com" />
    <updated>2022-03-15T05:35:08-05:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://texaswalkabout.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Can you wear brown boots with black cowboy hat? Explained!</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/can-you-wear-brown-boots-with-black-cowboy-hat/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/can-you-wear-brown-boots-with-black-cowboy-hat/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-15T05:35:08-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    The cowboy hat. It’s one of the most noticeable pieces of clothing out there. It shields the wearer from sun and rain, and also brings out the rugged coolness in just about anybody. Yet, are there unspoken rules for wearing one? In this article, we’ll&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>The cowboy hat. It’s one of the most noticeable pieces of clothing out there. It shields the wearer from sun and rain, and also brings out the rugged coolness in just about anybody.</p>
<p>Yet, are there unspoken rules for wearing one? In this article, we’ll go over some dos and don’ts regarding the famous (and somewhat infamous) cowboy hat, other things you can wear to match it, and what certain hat colors can mean.</p>
<h2><strong>What are the rules regarding the color of cowboy hats? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>Color won’t matter as much, but the rules of wearing cowboy hats will. </strong></p>
<p>Unless specified by a unique group of cowboy hat wearers, feel free to wear any hat color you want. Traditionally, colors don’t mean much, and whatever color your hat is depends on personal preferences.</p>
<p>For hot summer days, you’ll be better off wearing a hat that’s a light color, so that most of the sun’s rays will reflect off your head. This will help cool your overall body temperature. In contrast, black hats absorb the most heat, inevitably warming you up the more sun you get.</p>
<p>Now, when it comes to cowboy hat <em>behavior</em>, there are a few unspoken rules you might be expected to follow. For example, if you’re attending church for any reason, take your hat <em>off</em> while inside the building.</p>
<p>If you live in the US, it’s considered respectful to also remove your hat during the Pledge of Allegiance, Passing of the Flag or during the National Anthem. In some areas, it’s polite for men to take their cowboy hats off (or simply tip them) when introducing themselves to a lady.</p>
<p>It’s also considered good manners to place your cowboy hat upside down whenever you take it off. The origins of this practice might be practical in nature, as placing it that way will prevent the <a href="https://gamingsection.net/news/what-do-cowboy-hat-colors-mean-3/">brim from flattening</a> and help maintain the hats' original shape.</p>
<h2><strong>What does a black cowboy hat symbolize? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>In short, it can represent evil.</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.apparelsearch.com/terms/b/black_hat.html">Traditional western films</a> used white cowboy hats for good guys, while black cowboy hats were worn by the baddies. Even today's media has used the black cowboy hat to emphasize the evilness of just about any antagonist. Other popular bad guys such as Darth Vader and the Wicked Witch of the West also wore black headwear to represent their badness.</p>
<p>This isn’t to say you’ll become a villain in the eyes of others should you decide to wear one. In fact, the black cowboy hat is the <a href="https://gamingsection.net/news/what-do-cowboy-hat-colors-mean-3/">most popular</a> of its kind for both ladies and men.</p>
<h2><strong>Should you wear brown boots with a black cowboy hat? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>You don’t have to, but the combination will work!</strong></p>
<p>Either a black or white cowboy hat will match with just about any other color. If you want to rock a black hat and brown boots combo, go for it.</p>
<p>With that being said, it’s usually a good idea to avoid bright colors for your boots and other accessories such as your tie. You want <em>some</em> contrast, but anything too stark such as wearing bright red boots with your black cowboy hat will raise eyebrows.</p>
<h2><strong>Who should consider wearing brown boots with a black cowboy hat? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>Anyone! </strong></p>
<p>Unless the dress code at a formal gathering states otherwise, anyone can pull off brown boots and a black cowboy hat combination. The dark colors simply work well together in just about any setting.</p>
<p>However, for any event that has no western elements to speak of, it might be better to leave your hat and boots at home in favor of something else. You want to dress to impress. That’s understandable, but it also matters if you dress appropriately for the occasion.</p>
<h2><strong>Does cowboy hat color matter? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>It depends on certain holidays and what else you wear.</strong></p>
<p>As discussed before, the color can affect your body temperature depending on the season. Practicality aside, you can wear just about any cowboy hat color you choose, but pulling off a good look can become much harder the more western you want to appear.</p>
<p>In some cases, it’s more appropriate to wear <a href="https://gamingsection.net/news/what-do-cowboy-hat-colors-mean/">white straw</a> cowboy hats during Memorial Day through Labor Day. You’ll also fit in better if you wear a hat that corresponds to the color of your favorite sports team during a game.</p>
<p>When wearing other western-style clothes with your hat, the general rule of thumb is to compliment it with similar colors. Black cowboy hats will look better with darker colors, and vice versa when considering lighter colors. Remember the word <em>compliment</em>, meaning you want your outfit to stand out, but not too much (think bright neon colors or something equally weird).</p>
<h2><strong>Does a cowboy hat have to match the boots? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>Not really, but it would be a good idea. </strong></p>
<p>A black cowboy hat will go well with black cowboy boots, or even a brown pair. What’s more important, however, is the <em>theme</em> you’re trying to achieve. If you’re wearing a cowboy hat of any color in public, others <a href="https://www.seniorcare2share.com/does-cowboy-hat-have-to-match-boots/">will expect</a> to see you wearing a slick pair of cowboy boots to match. These two items tend to go together like bread and butter, it’s simply how the get-up has come to be.</p>
<h2><strong>Final Thoughts</strong></h2>
<p>Cowboy etiquette can be important, but something even more crucial is matching your cowboy hat with appropriate colors and style. Aim to be admired, not mocked.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>5 Things To Know About Wearing Cowboy Boots With Tuxedos  </title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/cowboy-boots-with-tuxedos/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/cowboy-boots-with-tuxedos/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-14T07:52:00-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Cowboy Boots With Tuxedos An important event is coming up. You hear that formal wear is expected. Your mind starts racing with all kinds of clothes that you can choose. There’s a nice tuxedo hanging in your closet, and a pair of cowboy boots to&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h2>Cowboy Boots With Tuxedos  </h2>
<p>An important event is coming up.</p>
<p>You hear that formal wear is expected. Your mind starts racing with all kinds of clothes that you can choose.</p>
<p>There’s a nice tuxedo hanging in your closet, and a pair of cowboy boots to match.</p>
<p>Although, is pairing the two a good idea? In this article, we’ll take a look at the finer details of a tuxedo and boot combination, the dos and don’ts of wearing them, and some alternatives in the odd case that the attire you have in mind simply won’t work.</p>
<h2><strong>Should you wear cowboy boots while wearing a tuxedo? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>It depends on where you’re going.</strong></p>
<p>If the host of the event makes a strict note to <em>not</em> wear cowboy boots and/or a tuxedo, then choose another kind of outfit all-together. The question, however, is not so much if you<em> should</em> wear the combo or not, but if you can pull it off in the first place.</p>
<p>Generally, Tuxedos are known to be a special type of formal wear that require specific kinds of shoes. Anything from classy Oxfords to <a href="https://bespokeunit.com/suits/tuxedos/shoes/">Calvin Klein Bernards</a> are considered more appropriate matches for tuxedo suits. This isn’t to say that you <em>can’t</em> wear cowboy boots at all when rocking a tux, just know that other kinds of footwear might be more appropriate depending on the event you’re attending.</p>
<p>If you want to try the tux and cowboy boot combination anyway, the number one thing you should avoid is bright colors, especially if certain accessories are in contrast to one another. For example, if your tuxedo is black, <em>don’t</em> pair it with bright red boots. Instead, have your footwear match your suit. Black boots, especially polished to a sleek glossy shine, will pair best with a black tuxedo.</p>
<p>If it’s available near you, the best match for cowboy boots is the famous <a href="https://www.gentlemansgazette.com/the-western-tuxedo/">western tuxedo</a>.</p>
<p>Prominent figures such as former US President George Bush Sr. were known to rock this combination in public.</p>
<p>To do this yourself, it’s important to take a detailed look at what’s considered the full western tuxedo appearance. In addition to your cowboy boots, you may also need a black cowboy hat and an over-sized belt buckle.</p>
<p>Also, putting on a pair of "boot-cut" jeans on top of all that wouldn’t be a bad idea either. If the western appearance is your ideal go-to, then it doesn’t hurt to go all out with it.</p>
<p>However, this get-up might not be appropriate for all formal gatherings. However, if you live in the southern US or a similar area, then don’t worry about wearing a tux and cowboy boots.</p>
<h2><strong>When should you consider wearing cowboy boots with a tuxedo? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>Location, location, location. </strong></p>
<p>This will sound like a repeated piece of advice, but <em>where</em> the event is being held can make all the difference in what you pick to wear. If the event you’re attending is a formal wedding, and it has no western themes to speak of, then it’s best that you pick other kinds of footwear other than cowboy boots.</p>
<p>Another example would be attending a fancy ball. The cultural clash of western and classy gala won’t mix well, and you’ll be getting the wrong kind of attention. If necessary, study the local fashion of where you’ll be going. You’re dressing to impress after all.</p>
<p>However, if you’re in <a href="https://rmkshoes.com/can-you-wear-cowboy-boots-with-a-suit/">Texas</a> or anywhere similar, then wearing both the tux and boots might be <em>expected</em>. For formal events in these areas, it’s common to have a <a href="https://www.gentlemansgazette.com/western-tuxedo-etiquette/">"black tie and boots"</a> dress code.</p>
<p>Remember the earlier advice recommending you avoid using bright colors? Well, it can matter, especially with men wearing slick tuxedos and polished cowboy boots. That’s right, these kinds of events expect your boots to shine like a brand-new mirror. So, regardless of which cowboy boots you pick to wear, give them a solid cleaning and polish before you head out.</p>
<h2><strong>What brand of boots goes well with a black tuxedo? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>There are many types, but the more important thing is giving your footwear a clean look.</strong></p>
<p>To be even more specific, polish your boots so well that you can see your face in them better than in your bathroom mirror. For any small scratches, you might be able to use <a href="https://bespokeunit.com/suits/tuxedos/shoes/">shoe cream</a> as a quick-fix, but if your footwear is made of other materials besides calfskin, it’ll be much harder to buff out any unsightly marks.</p>
<p>To compliment the tuxedo look, especially a western-style, consider getting a pair of boots made from <a href="https://rmkshoes.com/can-you-wear-cowboy-boots-with-a-suit/">cowhide, caiman, or lizard</a>. Bonus points if you can find any in glossy black.</p>
<p>It’s also recommended that you avoid using any brown cowboy boots. The reasoning goes back to when we talked about the need to avoid bright colors. The exception in this case would be pairing them with a nice brown tuxedo to match. What we’re trying to avoid are things that contrast and stand out to one another. It’s better if you match the tux and boot colors.</p>
<h2><strong>Final Thoughts</strong></h2>
<p>So, as a quick recap, don’t ignore the possibility that you’ll need different footwear altogether, avoid bright colors, and match your boots with whatever tux you decide on using. Accessories such as a tie should match the boots and suit as well.</p>
<p>Whatever you choose, keep a clean appearance. Don’t be afraid to add a bit of extra polish and elbow grease as well.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>7 Things To Know About WearingCowboy Boots Under Pants</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/cowboy-boots-under-pants/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/cowboy-boots-under-pants/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-13T18:29:04-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Do pants go over or under cowboy boots? It depends on the type of pants you are wearing as well as the gender of the person. Does this sound a bit confusing? Then keep reading this article. We will explain this topic in detail and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h1>Do pants go over or under cowboy boots?</h1>
<p><strong>It depends on the type of pants you are wearing as well as the gender of the person. Does this sound a bit confusing? Then keep reading this article. We will explain this topic in detail and clarify the mystery behind it.</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Can men wear their pants tucked into their cowboy boots?</h2>
<p><strong>The fashion experts say no, they cannot. Men typically wear wide-legged pants such as jeans or slacks. Those would look rather silly tucked into cowboy boots. </strong></p>
<p>Then there is the practicality aspect of it. Most jobs require men to be on the go a lot. When their pants are crammed into their cowboy boots it makes it difficult to move around. So, they are best off not doing it.</p>
<p>One last point is that constantly jamming the pants inside the boots can ruin them. Slacks, suit pants, or even jeans can become permanently creased or worn around the spot of the calves. You certainly don't want this to happen, right?</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Can women do it?</h2>
<p><strong>Women have more choices than men when it comes to tucking their pants into their boots. Many women wear leggings, tight-fitting jeans, or spandex-style pants which hug the lower legs. Pants such as these are meant to be tucked into a sweet pair of cowboy boots.</strong></p>
<p>There are times when the same woman will wear pants that are loose at the bottom. Examples of these would be bell-bottoms, loose-fitting jeans, slacks, or pantsuit bottoms. She has a choice of tucking the pants into the boots or letting them hang loose. Either is considered fashionable by style experts.</p>
<p>With women, the occasion plays a role in the answer. For a more formal occasion, she is better off letting the pants hang down over the boots. If she is riding a horse, a bicycle, a motorcycle, or moving around a lot, it is prudent to tuck the pants smoothly down into the boots.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Can kids wear their pants over their cowboy boots?</h2>
<p><strong>When they are involved in an activity, we would say no, do not. They are always running around or participating in some kind of sport. When doing so, the kids are more apt to trip over them and get hurt. During this time, it is best to tuck the pants into their cowboy boots.</strong></p>
<p>On the other hand, if you want them to look proper for school, religious services, or a visit with the grandparents, they can wear their pants over the boots. Especially if they are a dressier type of pants. Like women, kids have many options; sometimes with the assistance of their parents.</p>
<p>One great thing about being a kid wearing cowboy boots is they can get away with things that adults cannot. One of those things is the concept of wearing pants over their pants. Who knows? The child could be much more comfortable that way.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>When do you put cowboy boots under your pants?</h2>
<p><strong>Traditionally, it is anytime you are attending a formal occasion. It could be a business meeting, a fancy dinner party, perhaps even a wedding. At such events it is frowned upon to wear your pants inside your cowboy boots. </strong></p>
<p>As we discussed earlier, another time to do so is when you are working at a particularly active job. It is highly uncomfortable to have your pants bunched up inside the cowboy boots when moving around. Who wants to walk around like that anyhow?</p>
<p>Although you want room between the boots and your legs, you really don't want them to appear baggy. Pants look best when they are form-fitted and not sticking up out of your cowboy boots.</p>
<h2> </h2>
<h2>Should you be putting cowboy boots underneath jeans?</h2>
<p><strong>What many people do is buy their jeans specifically to wear with their cowboy boots. That way, they can make certain the jeans are form-fitting on the top part of the legs but wide enough on the bottom to properly fit over the boots. </strong></p>
<p>When shopping for jeans, we recommend bringing the boots you want to wear with them. Then try on various pairs of jeans to ensure you get the perfect fit. You want to look like your cowboy boots were made just for those jeans. This applies to men and women. My, how fabulous you will look!</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Final Thoughts</h2>
<p><strong>In the end, it is really up to the individual whether to wear their pants over or tucked into their cowboy boots. Nobody is going to put you in jail over an unpopular decision. You must do what is comfortable for yourself. Perhaps you disregard those folks who disagree with you. You know the old saying; if it feels good, do it!</strong></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>7 Tips For Wearing Dress cowboy boots With A Suit</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/dress-cowboy-boots-with-suit/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/dress-cowboy-boots-with-suit/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-13T10:14:13-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Do the fashion mavens think it is okay to wear dress cowboy boots with a suit or dress? That is what we are going to talk about in this concise article. If you care what people think of your attire and accessories, you will want&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Do the fashion mavens think it is okay to wear dress cowboy boots with a suit or dress? That is what we are going to talk about in this concise article. If you care what people think of your attire and accessories, you will want to read this.</p>
<h2>Can you wear dress cowboy boots with a suit?</h2>
<p>Many years ago the answer to this question would have been absolutely not. But, this is 2022. Society has changed and so has the ever-changing world of fashion. Today it is perfectly acceptable to wear cowboy boots with a man's suit or slacks, a woman's pantsuit, skirt or dress.</p>
<p>Does the style of the boots matter? In a sense, yes. The pair of boots you want to wear depends on the look you are trying to achieve. If you are wearing a casual outfit, the cowboy boots can be casual. If it is a formal occasion, a spiffier boot should be worn. Typically, if you are wearing a dressy suit, it is either for business or formal activities. Therefore, your cowboy boots ought to mirror your suit.</p>
<h2>When should you wear dress cowboy boots?</h2>
<p>It totally depends on the outfit you are wearing as well as the occasion. Not every style of dress cowboy boots will go with every suit. As we discussed in the previous paragraph, the boots ought to compliment the suit. For example, you would not wear thick winter boots with a lightweight dressy, formal suit.</p>
<p>Another instance would be the reverse. If it is cold outside, and you are wearing a heavy clad suit, then your thick winter boots will be fine. The occasion has something to do with it too. If it is a special occasion, and you are wearing an appropriately-styled suit, then your dress cowboy boots should compliment it. That goes for the color of your attire as well.</p>
<h2>What cowboy boots go good with suits?</h2>
<p>Ideally you ought to own many pairs of cowboy boots, one pair for every purpose that arises. Some should be dressy, some casual, others good for working or driving in. They also need to come in many colors, including at least one pair in black, one in brown, and one in tan.</p>
<p>That said, once again times have changed. A couple of decades ago, cowboy boots only came in a few designs, colors, and thicknesses. In today's marketplace there have to be literally hundreds of choices. It is up to you to select pairs that you love and are comfortable to wear. Additionally, it is best if you try them on before you buy them. That way you can make sure they fit well.</p>
<h2>What about women and dressy cowgirl boots?</h2>
<p>The same basic fashion rules apply to women as to men. They can wear dressy cowgirl boots with their business and formal attire. The boots need to compliment the outfit she is wearing. It is feasible to wear dressy boots with pantsuits, short dresses, and short skirt with a top combination.</p>
<p>Are there exceptions? Yes, if she is wearing a long dress or skirt it would probably look silly to wear cowboy boots with that. This is true even if the boots are a dressy pair. In that case, she really needs a different type of footwear. Other than that, it is up to the individual whether to wear dressy boots with her outfit.</p>
<h2>Can you wear cowboy boots with slacks?</h2>
<p>It is doable, yes. The same basic fashion rules apply here. Match up the appropriate boots with your slacks. The dressier your attire Is, the dressier your boots should be. This applies to men and women, children too if they like to wear cowboy boots.</p>
<p>One thing to make note of is you should NOT tuck your slacks (or suit pants) into your boots. Instead, they ought to be draped down over the boots. You can violate this fashion rule if you wish, but don't be surprised if people mock you.</p>
<h2>Are there certain brands and models of dress cowboy boots that you should have?</h2>
<p>As we said earlier, these days there are hundreds of boots to select from including dress cowboy boots. The kind you buy is totally up to you. Nobody is going to tell you what to do here. On the other hand, if you are looking for sound advice, we will offer some.</p>
<p>We won't tell you what kind of dress boots to buy, just suggest a strategy for choosing them. You are best off going into a brick-and-mortar store where you can view all the varieties and try them on. You want a pair that is comfortable as well as stylish. Otherwise, they will hurt your feet and wind up on the closet floor most of the time.</p>
<h2>Final Thoughts</h2>
<p>We can be your go-to source on how to choose a pair of dress cowboy boots. We are western wear fashion experts and will assist you in making your choices. That said, whether you wear dress boots or other superb footwear with your suit is completely up to you. Go ahead, buy them and enjoy them!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>5 Things To Know About Cowboy Boots For Truck Drivers</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/cowboy-boots-for-truck-drivers/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/cowboy-boots-for-truck-drivers/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-12T13:39:15-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/21/megan-bucknall-cAeVLl7NKLs-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                    Cowboy boots for truck drivers Do truck driving and cowboy boots go hand-in-hand? In the past, perhaps they did not. Nowadays, however, they definitely do. It depends on what kind you buy. In 2022, it is possible to find cowboy boots perfect for the truckers'&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/21/megan-bucknall-cAeVLl7NKLs-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                <h2>Cowboy boots for truck drivers</h2>
<p><strong>Do truck driving and cowboy boots go hand-in-hand? In the past, perhaps they did not. Nowadays, however, they definitely do. It depends on what kind you buy. In 2022, it is possible to find cowboy boots perfect for the truckers' lifestyle and work needs. Read on to find out more. </strong></p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Do truckers really wear cowboy boots?</h2>
<p><strong>Actually, many of them do. The stereotype is that truckers wear only cowboy boots with jeans. This is a bit of an overreach, not all of them do. However, there are quite a number that do and pretty much all the time. Some people are more comfortable in cowboy boots than any other type of footwear.</strong></p>
<p>For truckers, cowboy boots are multifunctional. They can be worn all day in the cabin of the big-rig. Then the boots can be worn into town at night into the bars and rest stops. The truck drivers can pick out one pair of boots that will suit every purpose during his road trip. He or she can never go wrong this way.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Are they comfortable in the cowboy boots?</h2>
<p><strong>They can be if the person has cowboy boots with a wider foot and toe area. When a trucker is shopping for his or her cowboy boots, the key is to pick out a pair that is comfortable to begin with. </strong></p>
<p>There are many manufacturers and styles of cowboy boots. It is up to each customer to select boots that are comfortable and still rugged enough to stand up to the many grueling hours on the road. He or she might also want to buy a pair that is waterproof since they are bound to encounter plenty of wet weather along the way.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Can truckers drive with cowboy boots on?</h2>
<p><strong>Yes they can, depending on the brand and model of boots they buy. If you go for pure style with the pointy toes and higher heels, it will likely be more difficult to drive. The key is to choose a pair that fits you well, and you know will be comfortable.</strong></p>
<p>It isn't like you buy cowboy boots totally blind. Most people go into a store and try on different brands and models until they find the perfect pair for themselves. As a truck driver, you know the kind of usage they will undergo, such as the long hours behind the wheel with your feet on the gas and brake pedals. It is up to you to select a pair that you can drive in.</p>
<h2> </h2>
<h2>What cowboy boots are best for truck drivers while working?</h2>
<p><strong>It would be helpful if you knew which brands and models were best suited to truckers in the first place. There are several we can recommend right off the bat. If you do not like these makers, you are free to choose one you do like. Again, the way to go is to try them on before you buy them. Here is our list to get you started.</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<ul>
<li>Ariat - Circuit Patriot Western Boot</li>
<li>The Cartwright from Tecovas</li>
<li>Groundbreaker Work Boot from Ariat in a few different models</li>
<li>Tecovas - The Earl</li>
<li>Wolverine - Men's Rancher Square Toe Boots</li>
<li>Irish Setter - Work Men's 83910 Marshall Boots</li>
<li>Ariat - Sport Patriot Western Boots</li>
<li>Tony Lama Leather Mid-Calf Western Boots</li>
<li>Lucchese - several different models available</li>
<li>Justin Men's Brown Leather Cowboy Boots</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<h2>Do cowboy boots have good traction?</h2>
<p><strong>In the past, the answer would have been no. In those days it was common for cowboy boots to be made with leather soles that were smooth on the bottom. They were rather slippery. Fast-forward to 2022 and boot makers have adjusted for this. </strong></p>
<p>Although it is still possible to purchase boots with smooth soles, it is also prevalent to find many models that are made with rubber soles. This makes for much better traction. Now truckers can wear stylish-looking cowboy boots that are better suited for working and for maneuvering on wet, slippery surfaces.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Final Thoughts</h2>
<p><strong>For truck drivers who prefer a stylish look to a rugged one, a great pair of cowboy boots is possible to find. You do not have to give up comfort and practicality in order to own and wear them.</strong></p>
<p>There are so many makers and models of cowboy boots that you are assured of finding multiple pairs that are perfect for your lifestyle. Why stop at one pair? Own several, one pair for each mood or occasion that comes into play. You will look terrific in them all too.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>8 Things To Know About Wearing Cowboy Boots During Winter</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/cowboy-boots-for-winter/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/cowboy-boots-for-winter/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-12T13:38:49-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                     Can you wear cowboy boots during the winter? Technically, yes you can; however, you must be careful about doing so. Most leather cowboy boots are water-resistant but not waterproof. If you intend to do this, you must first treat the boots with a special&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/20/megan-bucknall-cAeVLl7NKLs-unsplash.jpg" sizes="(min-width: 1260px) calc(3.22vw + 703px), (min-width: 900px) calc(50.59vw + 116px), (min-width: 840px) calc(5vw + 684px), calc(85.58vw + 23px)" srcset="https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/20/responsive/megan-bucknall-cAeVLl7NKLs-unsplash-xs.jpg 320w ,https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/20/responsive/megan-bucknall-cAeVLl7NKLs-unsplash-sm.jpg 480w ,https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/20/responsive/megan-bucknall-cAeVLl7NKLs-unsplash-md.jpg 768w"  alt="" width="5347" height="8000"></figure>
<h2>Can you wear cowboy boots during the winter?</h2>
<p><strong>Technically, yes you can; however, you must be careful about doing so. Most leather cowboy boots are water-resistant but not waterproof. If you intend to do this, you must first treat the boots with a special product designed to protect leather. If you do not, the snow and freezing rain could do permanent damage to them. </strong></p>
<p>If you have cowboy boots in a material other than leather, for example, suede, you must ascertain what kind of protection they need from winter snow and moisture. Suede is an even more delicate material than leather and would not stand up well to the wet atmosphere conditions of winter.</p>
<p>You are best off not wearing either suede or leather boots during the winter or rainy weather at any other time of year. There are many other types of footwear you can put on instead. If you ignore this advice, be prepared to need new cowboy boots every couple of years at least.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Should you wear cowboy boots during the winter?</h2>
<p><strong>Yes, as long as you protect them as we discussed. There are many advantages to wearing cowboy boots during the winter. For that matter, this can apply to spring and fall as well. Cowboy boots are typically tall, ranging from about 14 inches to 16 inches in height. </strong></p>
<p>Additionally, the leather composition is another advantage. Both the composition and the height of cowboy boots make the wearer feel very warm and toasty. This can come in handy during the chilly seasons and even the frigid winter season.</p>
<p>Please note, although the wearer might be a little hot with cowboy boots on during the summer months, they will protect his or her feet from the scorching summer sun. This is especially useful for people that work or spend leisure time outdoors.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>How do you snow or waterproof cowboy boots?</h2>
<p><strong>Keep in mind you cannot make leather cowboy boots totally waterproof. That is not the nature of leather. However, you can make them resistant to water, ice, and snow. For this we have some recommendations.</strong></p>
<p>First, when your boots get soaking wet, no matter what season or what caused the deluge of water onto the boots, let them dry naturally. Do not put them in direct sunlight or a similar heat source such as a portable heater.</p>
<p>Your best bet is to always protect them from the water in the first place. For that, generously apply some mink oil from a dry, clean, soft cloth. Slather the mink oil directly onto the leather sole and heel of your cowboy boots. You can apply the oil to the rest of the boot as well to make the entire item water-resistant. Do this at least once per month for the best results.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Can I wear my Ariat boots in the snow?</h2>
<p><strong>We have been discussing the practicality of wearing cowboy boots in the snow. We talked about how if you are going to wear them, you must protect them first. There is an exception to this rule. That exception is Ariat Hybrid Rancher Waterproof Western Boot. These boots are specifically made for winter's harsh weather.</strong></p>
<p>The Ariat boots are waterproof and insulated. They are most often seen on cowboys or cowgirls riding on horses. However, these boots can be worn by men or women who want to look stylish and still be protected from wet conditions. They are a practical solution for the problem of wearing cowboy boots in wet weather.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>What are the best cowboy boots for snow and wet weather?</h2>
<p><strong>As we have just mentioned, Ariat leads the pack. That said, there are a few other types that fit the bill well. These are all great in wet, cold weather for work, recreation, or play. We shall talk about these types now.</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<ul>
<li>Rocky Men's Insulated Pull-On Wellington Boots</li>
<li>Dan Post Boots Men's Albuquerque</li>
<li>Ariat Work Men's Workhog Composite Toe Boot</li>
<li>Women - Ariat Terrain Pull-On Waterproof Boots</li>
<li>Durango Women's Waterproof Composite Toe Western Boot</li>
<li>Ariat Hybrid Rancher Waterproof Cowgirl Boot</li>
<li>Twisted X Women's Cowboy Work Boots</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<h2>Are cowboy boots typically warm?</h2>
<p><strong>In a nutshell, yes they are extremely warm. Due to their sturdy composition of high-grade leather, plus the inner lining, the height of the boots, and the thickness of the soles, they simply ooze warmth. This makes them very sought after in cold weather climates and months.</strong></p>
<p>Like we talked about earlier, cowboy boots might be a little too warm in summer months. However, they will still protect your feet and lower legs from the intense heat of the season. Not to mention, they will also offer solid protection from the hard atmospheric conditions of working on the range or a ranch. Therefore, you can still wear them in hot weather.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Waterproof Insulated Cowboy Boots</h2>
<p><strong>You may be wondering if the cost and effort of waterproofing cowboy boots is worth it. The answer is definitely yes. Think of how much you spent on the boots to begin with. Then think about all the wet weather you have wherever you live.</strong></p>
<p>Even if it doesn't literally snow much, it probably rains a lot. Rain is just as harmful to your boots as snow. Now think about the cost of repeatedly repairing your boots. Or how about having to buy a new pair every couple of years. Now ask yourself if waterproofing them is worth the money and time. We think you see our point!</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Final Thoughts</h2>
<p><strong>The whole point of this article is that, yes you can wear cowboy boots in the winter if you take proper precautions. If you have plenty of money to spend on new boots every couple of years, then you can ignore our advice. It is totally up to you!</strong></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>5 things to know about Cowboy boots with turned up toes</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/cowboy-boots-with-turned-up-toes/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/cowboy-boots-with-turned-up-toes/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-12T06:27:20-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Cowboy boots with turned up toes Perhaps you’re thinking of getting a pair of cowboy boots, or are just curious about all the different types and seeing what the fuss is all about. Whether you’re in it to wear them or just want a bit&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h2>Cowboy boots with turned up toes</h2>
<p>Perhaps you’re thinking of getting a pair of cowboy boots, or are just curious about all the different types and seeing what the fuss is all about.</p>
<p>Whether you’re in it to wear them or just want a bit of knowledge to satisfy that curious itch in your mind, know that cowboy boots are made for certain lifestyles.</p>
<p>This kind of footwear either provides comfort and versatility for rugged work, or makes a bold statement.</p>
<p>In this article, we’ll discuss why turned up toes are used for cowboy boots, why Mexicans find pointy boots so popular, and the different shapes that pointed cowboy boots can take.</p>
<h2><strong>Why do cowboy boots have turned-up toes? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>Traditionally, it’s to make horse-riding easier. </strong></p>
<p>That point on the boot is there, making it easier for horse riders to put their feet into stirrups.</p>
<p>In addition, a special angle around the ball of the foot is added so that the boots become locked in place once inserted.</p>
<p>Interestingly enough, this design originated as far back as <a href="https://artsandculture.google.com/story/the-high-life-a-history-of-men-in-heels/iQJCgMgwSKV5Kw">10th century</a> in the form of what we know today as high heels.</p>
<p>Originally, the high heel was used primarily by men, making it easier to ride horses, and to keep steady when firing arrows from their trusty steeds.</p>
<p>Even famous bands such as Motley Crue may have used them in many of their live performances.</p>
<p>Aside from practicality, pointed-toed boots are mostly used as a popular fashion choice.</p>
<p>Ever since the early 2000’s, pointed toe cowboy boots have become all the rage among western men and women alike.</p>
<h2><strong>What is the point of Mexican pointy boots? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>The short answer is popularity.</strong></p>
<p>Also called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mexican_pointy_boots">trival boots</a>, or “<em>botas tribaleras</em>” in Spanish, these kinds of footwear are mostly worn by Mexican men who take part in what’s referred to as “trival” music.</p>
<p>Also known as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tribal_guarachero">tribal guarachero</a>, this brand is a fusion of regional Mexican music genres and electronic dance music.</p>
<p>Whereas the actual origin of these boots remains uncertain, some sources state that trival boots came from the Mexican state of Nuevo Leon, Monterrey in 2009.</p>
<p>The style then spread to various areas in the US such as Oklahoma, Tennessee, Mississippi, and Dallas, Texas.</p>
<p>Aside from being an eye-catching fashion statement, guys who wear these boots participate in group dance-offs at local nightclubs.</p>
<p>Some groups take great effort into coordinating their moves, and can spend weeks on end to get their routines just right. This isn’t just for show either, the winning groups of these contests have been known to win up to $500 in prize money.</p>
<p>The more popular dance troupes have been hired to entertain for bachelorette parties and even weddings.</p>
<h2><strong>What are pointed toe cowboy boots called? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>It depends on the type of pointed toe.</strong></p>
<p>The pointed toe was originally made for versatility. Today, it serves much of the same function, and not just for getting your foot into a stirrup.</p>
<p>If a boot has a very sharp point, it’s referred to as <a href="https://stageswest.com/blog/how-to-choose-a-toe-shape-for-your-boots/">"needle pointed."</a>. If the toe has a tip that’s slightly blunted instead, it’s then referred to as a “snip toe.” Anything in-between those types is called “J toe.”</p>
<p>There’s also the <a href="https://www.ariat.com/al/cowboy-boots-square-toe-vs-pointed-toe">square toe</a>, a kind of boot that’s used for general outdoor work. Whereas the traditional pointed toe is used for both horse riding and formal events, the square toe can also be used as a dress boot as well as anything that involves constant walking.</p>
<p>Some other types include the cutter toe, the round toe, and the regular square. The name is defined as such, depending on the amount of foot space that each boot allows.</p>
<p>Should any of these kinds interest you, look at your own foot size to determine which kind of cowboy boot toe is best.</p>
<p>Anything with a pointy tip will usually be a bit tighter, and might require a certain level of swagger just to pull off.</p>
<p>If you’re looking for something more casual, it’s recommended that you pick a more blunt-tipped style of boot to allow more foot room, and therefore, more comfort.</p>
<p>Unless you’re a hardcore rancher or do a lot of horse-back riding, getting pointed tipped boots may not be a good idea. The thinner tip has been known to make general walking uncomfortable, so before you decide on buying a pair of any kind of cowboy boots, make sure you know what you’ll use them for.</p>
<h2><strong>Final thoughts</strong></h2>
<p>Now that you have equipped yourself with a bit more knowledge than you had before, you might be more confident in trying out some turned-up cowboy boots yourself. Or, if you’re bold enough, grab a pair of flashy trival boots and join a Mexican dancing troupe.</p>
<p>Whereas style is important for various reasons, pick a type that’s most comfortable for you and your purposes. You don’t want to find yourself out on the ranch or on the dance floor just to have your toes start aching with pain after an hour or so of use.</p>
<p>Regardless of your personality or reasons, know that the pointed tip on cowboy boots is there for a reason, and not just an expression of fashion. The style itself may change depending on cultural fads, or even to serve some practical purpose we are not yet aware of, but know that pointed toes will be hanging around for quite a while.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>What shoes to wear with cowboy hat (Explained)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/what-shoes-to-wear-with-cowboy-hat/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/what-shoes-to-wear-with-cowboy-hat/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-11T09:17:20-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Believe it or not, the answer to this question is varied. It is most common to wear boots with a cowboy hat, especially if they are cowboy boots. However, it is also fashionable to wear dress shoes or casual shoes with one, just not sandals.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><strong>Believe it or not, the answer to this question is varied. It is most common to wear boots with a cowboy hat, especially if they are cowboy boots. </strong></p>
<p><strong>However, it is also fashionable to wear dress shoes or casual shoes with one, just not sandals. It greatly depends on the occasion. For more information on this subject, keep reading this article. </strong></p>
<h2>How to match cowboy hat to boots</h2>
<p><strong>Is this important? In actuality, yes; but many people fail to do this, and they survive just fine. </strong></p>
<p><strong>Nobody really notices. Ideally though, you should wear a hat that matches your boots. Would you like some examples? </strong></p>
<p><strong>Keep reading!</strong></p>
<p>If it is a formal occasion, you want your hat and boot color to go with your suit jacket and pants.</p>
<p><a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/grey-suit-with-cowboy-boots/">They can either be a match or a complimentary contrasting color. In either case, you will want your hat and boots to match for the best look.</a></p>
<p>Technically, the material of the hat and boots should also match.</p>
<p>For instance, if you are wearing a suede cowboy hat, you would be best off wearing suede cowboy boots. People don't always pay attention to this rule.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Can you wear a cowboy hat with shoes?</h2>
<p><strong>It depends on whom you are dressing for. There are some purists who feel that wearing anything other than boots with a cowboy hat is a sin. The rest of the public does not feel this way and tends to ignore the purists.</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/black-suit-with-brown-cowboy-boots/">In essence, yes you can wear shoes with a cowboy hat; but the type of shoes you wear is relevant.</a></p>
<p>You can wear a nice pair of dress shoes and look extremely handsome. As we already mentioned though, wearing sandals is a no-no.</p>
<p>If you are working or riding on a horse when wearing a cowboy hat, nobody will give you flack if you wear sneakers. <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/what-are-the-best-jeans-to-wear-with-cowboy-boots/">You may look a little silly that way, but who cares if you are comfortable in them?</a> Wear sneakers or shoes if you want!</p>
<h2>Are there specific fashion rules for wearing dress shoes with a cowboy hat?</h2>
<p><strong>Once again, it depends on the occasion. </strong></p>
<p><strong>If it is a formal event, dress shoes should be worn. If the person would rather wear boots, then a dressy pair of cowboy boots is appropriate and looks fine to others.</strong></p>
<p>Another factor is where the person is. In much of American nowadays, a cowboy hat is seldom worn. <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/do-you-tuck-your-pants-in-cowboy-boots/">If someone in the northeastern United States is wearing one, they will likely be mocked.</a> Of course, if they are in either the west or southwest, it is common and revered.</p>
<p>Your best bet is to wear shoes with a material and a color to match your cowboy hat.</p>
<p><a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/do-you-tuck-your-pants-in-cowboy-boots/">This is extremely fashionable, and you will look quite dashing.</a></p>
<h2>Do you have to wear boots with a cowboy hat?</h2>
<p><strong>While it is not illegal not to wear the boots; fashion mavens insist that boots are a must if you are going to wear the cowboy hat. </strong></p>
<p><strong>Consider this! If you are wearing a black cowboy hat with black dress boots, you will look sensational. Especially if the hat and boots are made of leather or another fine material.</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/do-you-tuck-your-pants-in-cowboy-boots/">If you do not have a pair of boots, then a slick-looking pair of dress shoes of a similar style to the hat will do fine.</a></p>
<p>A more formal appearance will be achieved by wearing cowboy boots with a cowboy hat.</p>
<p>Please note, if you are wearing a boot of any other type than a cowboy boot when you are wearing a cowboy hat, some people might think you look ridiculous. <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/can-you-wear-a-fedora-with-cowboy-boots/">However, if you don't care what those people think, go ahead and wear them.</a></p>
<h2>What about women?</h2>
<p><strong>Generally the same fashion rules apply to a woman wearing shoes with a cowgirl hat as they do for men. </strong></p>
<p><strong>It depends on where she is as well as the occasion. Again, if she lives in the west or southwest, it is appropriate for her to wear a cowgirl hat. In that case, if she wants to wear shoes with it, dressier kinds look best.</strong></p>
<p>On the other hand, if she lives anyplace else, she might look rather silly in a cowgirl hat. However, the United States is a free country. So, if she chooses to wear one anyhow, that is her right and nobody will ever stop her.</p>
<p><a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/grey-suit-with-cowboy-boots/">As with the men, if a woman wants to appear as a fashion plate, she should wear cowgirl boots with a cowgirl hat.</a> She should try to match the colors and material types for the best look possible.</p>
<h2>Where is it normal to wear a cowboy hat?</h2>
<p><strong>As we have been alluding to, this completely depends on where he is and the occasion. If a man of the west is attending a formal occasion, then wearing a cowboy hat with his attire IS dressing up. In this case, he would wear an especially fine hat. Chances are he owns a number of cowboy hats anyhow, one for each purpose.</strong></p>
<p>It is also prudent to wear one while performing his cowboy duties on the range or a ranch. Normally, this would be while riding his or her horse. <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/do-you-tuck-your-pants-in-cowboy-boots/">In such a case, he should wear work-oriented cowboy boots with the rest of his outfit.</a></p>
<h2>Final Thoughts</h2>
<p><strong>Keep in mind, even at casual events but especially at formal ones, it is proper etiquette to remove the hat upon entering the building or room. </strong></p>
<p><strong>This is true of any type of hat in addition to a cowboy one. It is also okay to wear shoes when wearing the cowboy hat as long as they are meant for that level of formality. </strong></p>
<p><strong>Again, this is a free country. If you want to wear the shoes with the hat, go right ahead!</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>5 Things To Know About Wearing A Grey suit with cowboy boots</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/grey-suit-with-cowboy-boots/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/grey-suit-with-cowboy-boots/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-11T06:34:00-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Grey suit with cowboy boots You want to dress for success. Or you want to dress for a night of fun, but you want to look good in front of all your friends, family, and peers. Despite dressing for formality or just wanting to let&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h2 class="p1">Grey suit with cowboy boots<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></h2>
<p>You want to dress for success. Or you want to dress for a night of fun, but you want to look good in front of all your friends, family, and peers. Despite dressing for formality or just wanting to let off a bit of steam, looking good can make you <em>feel</em> good.</p>
<p>An important occasion is coming up, and you want to try out some cowboy boots and a grey suit combination. Yet, is the combo you have in your mind the best choice? What will others think? Worry not, for we’ll discuss which boots can work with grey suits, and the fine details that will bring out the style <em>and</em> confidence.</p>
<h2><strong>How can you pair cowboy boots with a grey suit? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>The answer lies in your attitude.</strong></p>
<p>The question you should be asking yourself isn’t whether your clothes are worthy of you, it’s if <em>you’re</em> worthy of your clothes. When pairing <em>any</em> suit with cowboy boots, how you carry yourself matters.</p>
<p>Wearing both a suit and cowboy boots outside of Texas is described as a: <a href="https://www.dmarge.com/how-to-wear-boots-with-suit">"big and bold statement."</a> If you haven’t already, brush up on your swagger.</p>
<p>If you’re feeling a bit overwhelmed at the moment, don’t sweat, because you don't need the charisma of a Country Super star just to pull off the look you’re going for. What can help you in the short term is learning how to <a href="https://www.wikihow.com/Walk-with-Confidence">walk with confidence</a>. Once you practice this advice often enough, you’ll start to feel <em>great</em> in your grey suit and cowboy boots combo. With enough time and effort, others will start to notice as well, and admire you for it.</p>
<h2><strong>Should you wear a grey suit with cowboy boots? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>You can, if you know how to pull it off.</strong></p>
<p>Now you’re asking yourself not if you can pull off the grey suit and boots, but <em>should</em> you? Having a confident attitude may be important to achieve it, but don’t skip the details as well. Specifically, suit accessories such as the right shirt and tie.</p>
<p>A great choice of shirt to go with whichever hue of grey suit you own is a white one. However, it’s not the only color that can work. Navy, pink, and blue are all colors that will pair nicely with grey. Whichever your choice, the shirt should look clean and crisp. Take your time to give it a good wash, optional bleach, and a solid ironing to make it look the best.</p>
<p>Next up is the tie. Again, the color is what you should focus on. Popular choices include “true blue,” maroon, forest green, and red.</p>
<p>The shading can matter too, as you want your tie to stand out (you’re working on your swagger, remember?), so whichever shirt/tie combination you choose, if one is dark, the other should be lighter.</p>
<h2><strong>What color boots go well with a grey suit? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>Options are a bit limited, but you can be flexible with them.</strong></p>
<p>It’s more than likely that the most important piece is the cowboy boots themselves. For grey suits, it’s recommended you go with either brown, cherry black, or plain black for the boot color.</p>
<p>Darker colors might be better in the case of a <em>light</em> grey suit. Darker grey suits can pair well with brown shoes, as the hues will be similar and won’t risk a color clash.</p>
<p>On an important note, these colors can also be used on different kinds of boots altogether. We’ll touch up on that a bit later.</p>
<p><strong>Bonus content: There are other types of boots!</strong></p>
<p>You’re your own boss, so whichever pair of boots you want to wear on your feet, that’s that. However, that being said, it’s always a good idea to expand your options.</p>
<p>For example, you can go with a nice-looking pair of oxfords, <a href="https://www.wikihow.com/Walk-with-Confidence">"capped toes"</a>, or even your own dress shoes (if you already own a pair), as long as they are burgundy or black. Consider doing this instead if your cowboy boots are bright in color.</p>
<p>Other options that will work great with a grey suit are <a href="https://www.amazon.ca/Clarks-Mens-Chukka-Nubuc-Numeric_10_Point_5/dp/B08FVHXL8L/ref=asc_df_B08FVHXL8L/?tag=googleshopc0c-20&amp;linkCode=df0&amp;hvadid=570082828694&amp;hvpos=&amp;hvnetw=g&amp;hvrand=17643113985851333354&amp;hvpone=&amp;hvptwo=&amp;hvqmt=&amp;hvdev=c&amp;hvdvcmdl=&amp;hvlocint=&amp;hvlocphy=9001319&amp;hvtargid=pla-1434520040774&amp;psc=1">Chukka boots</a>, and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Generic1-Chelsea-Anti-Slip-Waterproof-Business/dp/B08Y8RHVS7">Chelsea</a>-style footwear. These types have been known to be more “stylish,” meaning they’re great for formal occasions.</p>
<p>If you <a href="https://www.dmarge.com/how-to-wear-boots-with-suit">tailor your dress pants</a> right, you can try out boots made by RM Williams. Just another side note, that’s another thing you should iron and clean correctly, because gaining confidence can be hard when everyone’s smiling at all your pant crinkles.</p>
<p>Whichever of these you think is the best second choice, it’s recommended that you get a pair that’s in leather.</p>
<p>Leather, especially polished, tends to have a more refined look whenever it’s paired with a suit. Bonus points if you can do that with lighter colors, such as brown.</p>
<p>When it comes down to it, cowboy boots are fine. Just don’t forget that you have other options.</p>
<h2><strong>Final Thoughts</strong></h2>
<p>Whereas the suit can make the man, the man can also make the suit. If you’ve looked at yourself many times in the mirror with your chosen combo and still don’t approve, at least try walking inside your home for a while. Keep your chin up, and eyes straight ahead.</p>
<p>If you can, get some of your buddies to dress the same! Being around people you’re familiar with can help shrug off some of the nervous feelings while in public. You’re just trying to make a fashion statement, not attend a funeral.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Want To Wear Cowboy Boots Under Wedding Dress? 5 Tips To Follow</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/cowboy-boots-under-wedding-dress/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/cowboy-boots-under-wedding-dress/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-11T06:34:06-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    A wedding can be the most important moment in a woman’s life. On top of all the invitations, plans, catering, she also has to carefully consider what she wears. Not only does she want her future husband impressed and love-struck with awe by her appearance,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>A wedding can be the most important moment in a woman’s life.</p>
<p>On top of all the invitations, plans, catering, she also has to carefully consider what she wears. Not only does she want her future husband impressed and love-struck with awe by her appearance, she wants the wedding guests to be amazed too!</p>
<p>In this article, we’ll discuss whether wearing cowboy boots underneath a wedding dress is appropriate, and ways in which the combination can work.</p>
<h2><strong>Can you wear cowboy boots underneath a wedding dress? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>Yes you can, just be aware of the terrain!</strong></p>
<p>The real heart of the issue isn’t whether you <em>can</em> wear cowboy boots to your wedding or not. Just about anyone can wear boots anytime they please. It’s a matter of your personal choices and the environment.</p>
<p>Let’s talk a bit about practicality.</p>
<p>If you’re having your wedding in the great outdoors, within a rustic barn, or even nearby horse stables (these are just examples, the style of the wedding is up to you), wearing cowboy boots will not only be theme-appropriate, but will also prevent you from spraining your ankle during the ceremony.</p>
<p>Traditional wedding footwear such as high-heels won’t function very well on dirt, gravel, mud, or grass.</p>
<p>If you have to spend large amounts of time outside on rugged terrain during your special event, consider slipping on your best pair of cowboy boots for both function and form.</p>
<p>Whereas rugged boots might seem more of a masculine approach, keep in mind the ground that you’ll be walking on.</p>
<p>Nature isn’t known to have smooth, flat surfaces for treading, so it might be a good idea to wear something that will carry you in comfort, especially during an event as important as your wedding.</p>
<h2><strong>Should you wear cowboy boots underneath a wedding dress? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>Again, wearing or not wearing them is a matter of choice.</strong></p>
<p>In our western world, the bride has <em>a huge</em> influence over choosing what goes into a wedding. If you’re already considering wearing cowboy boots for your special day, go ahead!</p>
<p>Heck, you could even ask all your friends and family to do the same!</p>
<p>Choosing to wear them is also a matter of confidence. Does it feel fun to wear cowboy boots?</p>
<p>Do you love country dancing on the dance floor all night long? If any of the previous questions gets you excited, then cowboy boots are a perfect choice!</p>
<p>You don’t have to be wild and crazy just to appreciate them either. As mentioned earlier, the wedding theme is important too.</p>
<p>Should the background match, taking pictures with your stylish boots will leave you and your family with fun memories for years to come.</p>
<p>Another reminder, the ground you’ll be walking on should be considered as well. No bride wants to stumble all over the place because she didn’t wear something functional enough.</p>
<p>To save yourself from any potential embarrassment (or worse, serious harm), make sure the footwear you choose, cowboy boots or whatever else, is practical enough to serve your wishes.</p>
<h2><strong>What cowboy boots can go well with a wedding dress? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>It’s recommended you choose style over function, and there are multiple options to pick from. </strong></p>
<p>With that being said, at the very least, whatever pair of dress boots you choose, test them on uneven ground should the need arise.</p>
<p>Even though Lacey boots are more appropriate for weddings, they should come with a degree of toughness as well.</p>
<p>If you’re willing to go all out on the looks, try shopping for some custom-made boots that the <a href="https://www.amazon.ca/s?k=Lucchese+cowboy+boots&amp;linkCode=gs3&amp;linkId=23c75ae5e2be718d98b8c10b83e4865e&amp;tag=asset1048ca00-20">Lucchese</a> brand is well-known for.</p>
<p>However, keep in mind that the price tag for this kind of footwear is expensive, and can be thousands of dollars for a single pair!</p>
<p>For those on a budget, or simply don’t want to dish out a couple grand just for some wedding boots, <a href="https://www.amazon.ca/s?k=justin+cowboy+boots&amp;linkCode=gs3&amp;linkId=817631ea4271a54c9f91f7d5e88d4f12&amp;tag=asset1048ca00-20">Justin</a> and <a href="https://www.amazon.ca/s?k=Corral+cowboy+boots&amp;linkCode=gs3&amp;linkId=c5f27c15c9ddca31c9cc03855a4fa856&amp;tag=asset1048ca00-20">Corral</a> are decent brands to consider as well.</p>
<p>Both these companies offer boots that are tough, stylish, and affordable.</p>
<p>If you’re still unsure, pick multiple pairs that you think would go great with your wedding attire, and ask some of your close family members and friends for their opinions.</p>
<p>It helps to not only feel great in your cowboy boots, but also be <em>seen</em> in them as well.</p>
<h2><strong>Will a short wedding dress look good with cowboy boots?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Yes, yes it would.</strong></p>
<p>A short wedding dress will not only show off your boots more, but it’s highly recommended that you do so for this purpose. What’s the point of wearing cowboy boots in the first place if your dress is too long for others to see?</p>
<p>To get more specific, the type of short dress you’ll choose can matter.</p>
<p>The appropriate length should be about mid-calf hemline or knee-length.</p>
<p>For overall style, consider picking a lace or western-style dress that will compliment your chosen pair of cowboy boots. If the combination looks great, feels great, and elicits compliments from your friends and family, then you’ve found the right look!</p>
<h2><strong>Final Thoughts</strong></h2>
<p>It’s <em>your</em> special day, the final choice of what you wear is what you want the most.</p>
<p>Aside from the choices already mentioned, you can also check out this <a href="https://bridalmusings.com/175679/boot-barn-cowboy-boots-for-your-wedding/">website</a>, or even this <a href="https://www.bootbarn.com/womens/featured/wedding-collection/?utm_source=PR&amp;utm_medium=PR_Placement&amp;utm_campaign=BridalCampaign_BridalMusings_JUNE">one</a> for more options on how to make your western wedding dreams come true. There’s even a simple <a href="http://mckinneyswesternstore.com/wear-cowboy-boots-wedding-dress/">guide</a> you can use to make your wedding the best day it can be.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
