<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Texas Walkabout</title>
    <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com" />
    <updated>2022-03-12T13:39:15-06:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://texaswalkabout.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>5 Things To Know About Cowboy Boots For Truck Drivers</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/cowboy-boots-for-truck-drivers/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/cowboy-boots-for-truck-drivers/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-12T13:39:15-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/21/megan-bucknall-cAeVLl7NKLs-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                    Cowboy boots for truck drivers Do truck driving and cowboy boots go hand-in-hand? In the past, perhaps they did not. Nowadays, however, they definitely do. It depends on what kind you buy. In 2022, it is possible to find cowboy boots perfect for the truckers'&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/21/megan-bucknall-cAeVLl7NKLs-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                <h2>Cowboy boots for truck drivers</h2>
<p><strong>Do truck driving and cowboy boots go hand-in-hand? In the past, perhaps they did not. Nowadays, however, they definitely do. It depends on what kind you buy. In 2022, it is possible to find cowboy boots perfect for the truckers' lifestyle and work needs. Read on to find out more. </strong></p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Do truckers really wear cowboy boots?</h2>
<p><strong>Actually, many of them do. The stereotype is that truckers wear only cowboy boots with jeans. This is a bit of an overreach, not all of them do. However, there are quite a number that do and pretty much all the time. Some people are more comfortable in cowboy boots than any other type of footwear.</strong></p>
<p>For truckers, cowboy boots are multifunctional. They can be worn all day in the cabin of the big-rig. Then the boots can be worn into town at night into the bars and rest stops. The truck drivers can pick out one pair of boots that will suit every purpose during his road trip. He or she can never go wrong this way.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Are they comfortable in the cowboy boots?</h2>
<p><strong>They can be if the person has cowboy boots with a wider foot and toe area. When a trucker is shopping for his or her cowboy boots, the key is to pick out a pair that is comfortable to begin with. </strong></p>
<p>There are many manufacturers and styles of cowboy boots. It is up to each customer to select boots that are comfortable and still rugged enough to stand up to the many grueling hours on the road. He or she might also want to buy a pair that is waterproof since they are bound to encounter plenty of wet weather along the way.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Can truckers drive with cowboy boots on?</h2>
<p><strong>Yes they can, depending on the brand and model of boots they buy. If you go for pure style with the pointy toes and higher heels, it will likely be more difficult to drive. The key is to choose a pair that fits you well, and you know will be comfortable.</strong></p>
<p>It isn't like you buy cowboy boots totally blind. Most people go into a store and try on different brands and models until they find the perfect pair for themselves. As a truck driver, you know the kind of usage they will undergo, such as the long hours behind the wheel with your feet on the gas and brake pedals. It is up to you to select a pair that you can drive in.</p>
<h2> </h2>
<h2>What cowboy boots are best for truck drivers while working?</h2>
<p><strong>It would be helpful if you knew which brands and models were best suited to truckers in the first place. There are several we can recommend right off the bat. If you do not like these makers, you are free to choose one you do like. Again, the way to go is to try them on before you buy them. Here is our list to get you started.</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<ul>
<li>Ariat - Circuit Patriot Western Boot</li>
<li>The Cartwright from Tecovas</li>
<li>Groundbreaker Work Boot from Ariat in a few different models</li>
<li>Tecovas - The Earl</li>
<li>Wolverine - Men's Rancher Square Toe Boots</li>
<li>Irish Setter - Work Men's 83910 Marshall Boots</li>
<li>Ariat - Sport Patriot Western Boots</li>
<li>Tony Lama Leather Mid-Calf Western Boots</li>
<li>Lucchese - several different models available</li>
<li>Justin Men's Brown Leather Cowboy Boots</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<h2>Do cowboy boots have good traction?</h2>
<p><strong>In the past, the answer would have been no. In those days it was common for cowboy boots to be made with leather soles that were smooth on the bottom. They were rather slippery. Fast-forward to 2022 and boot makers have adjusted for this. </strong></p>
<p>Although it is still possible to purchase boots with smooth soles, it is also prevalent to find many models that are made with rubber soles. This makes for much better traction. Now truckers can wear stylish-looking cowboy boots that are better suited for working and for maneuvering on wet, slippery surfaces.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Final Thoughts</h2>
<p><strong>For truck drivers who prefer a stylish look to a rugged one, a great pair of cowboy boots is possible to find. You do not have to give up comfort and practicality in order to own and wear them.</strong></p>
<p>There are so many makers and models of cowboy boots that you are assured of finding multiple pairs that are perfect for your lifestyle. Why stop at one pair? Own several, one pair for each mood or occasion that comes into play. You will look terrific in them all too.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>8 Things To Know About Wearing Cowboy Boots During Winter</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/cowboy-boots-for-winter/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/cowboy-boots-for-winter/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-12T13:38:49-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                     Can you wear cowboy boots during the winter? Technically, yes you can; however, you must be careful about doing so. Most leather cowboy boots are water-resistant but not waterproof. If you intend to do this, you must first treat the boots with a special&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/20/megan-bucknall-cAeVLl7NKLs-unsplash.jpg" sizes="(min-width: 1260px) calc(3.22vw + 703px), (min-width: 900px) calc(50.59vw + 116px), (min-width: 840px) calc(5vw + 684px), calc(85.58vw + 23px)" srcset="https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/20/responsive/megan-bucknall-cAeVLl7NKLs-unsplash-xs.jpg 320w ,https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/20/responsive/megan-bucknall-cAeVLl7NKLs-unsplash-sm.jpg 480w ,https://texaswalkabout.com/media/posts/20/responsive/megan-bucknall-cAeVLl7NKLs-unsplash-md.jpg 768w"  alt="" width="5347" height="8000"></figure>
<h2>Can you wear cowboy boots during the winter?</h2>
<p><strong>Technically, yes you can; however, you must be careful about doing so. Most leather cowboy boots are water-resistant but not waterproof. If you intend to do this, you must first treat the boots with a special product designed to protect leather. If you do not, the snow and freezing rain could do permanent damage to them. </strong></p>
<p>If you have cowboy boots in a material other than leather, for example, suede, you must ascertain what kind of protection they need from winter snow and moisture. Suede is an even more delicate material than leather and would not stand up well to the wet atmosphere conditions of winter.</p>
<p>You are best off not wearing either suede or leather boots during the winter or rainy weather at any other time of year. There are many other types of footwear you can put on instead. If you ignore this advice, be prepared to need new cowboy boots every couple of years at least.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Should you wear cowboy boots during the winter?</h2>
<p><strong>Yes, as long as you protect them as we discussed. There are many advantages to wearing cowboy boots during the winter. For that matter, this can apply to spring and fall as well. Cowboy boots are typically tall, ranging from about 14 inches to 16 inches in height. </strong></p>
<p>Additionally, the leather composition is another advantage. Both the composition and the height of cowboy boots make the wearer feel very warm and toasty. This can come in handy during the chilly seasons and even the frigid winter season.</p>
<p>Please note, although the wearer might be a little hot with cowboy boots on during the summer months, they will protect his or her feet from the scorching summer sun. This is especially useful for people that work or spend leisure time outdoors.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>How do you snow or waterproof cowboy boots?</h2>
<p><strong>Keep in mind you cannot make leather cowboy boots totally waterproof. That is not the nature of leather. However, you can make them resistant to water, ice, and snow. For this we have some recommendations.</strong></p>
<p>First, when your boots get soaking wet, no matter what season or what caused the deluge of water onto the boots, let them dry naturally. Do not put them in direct sunlight or a similar heat source such as a portable heater.</p>
<p>Your best bet is to always protect them from the water in the first place. For that, generously apply some mink oil from a dry, clean, soft cloth. Slather the mink oil directly onto the leather sole and heel of your cowboy boots. You can apply the oil to the rest of the boot as well to make the entire item water-resistant. Do this at least once per month for the best results.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Can I wear my Ariat boots in the snow?</h2>
<p><strong>We have been discussing the practicality of wearing cowboy boots in the snow. We talked about how if you are going to wear them, you must protect them first. There is an exception to this rule. That exception is Ariat Hybrid Rancher Waterproof Western Boot. These boots are specifically made for winter's harsh weather.</strong></p>
<p>The Ariat boots are waterproof and insulated. They are most often seen on cowboys or cowgirls riding on horses. However, these boots can be worn by men or women who want to look stylish and still be protected from wet conditions. They are a practical solution for the problem of wearing cowboy boots in wet weather.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>What are the best cowboy boots for snow and wet weather?</h2>
<p><strong>As we have just mentioned, Ariat leads the pack. That said, there are a few other types that fit the bill well. These are all great in wet, cold weather for work, recreation, or play. We shall talk about these types now.</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<ul>
<li>Rocky Men's Insulated Pull-On Wellington Boots</li>
<li>Dan Post Boots Men's Albuquerque</li>
<li>Ariat Work Men's Workhog Composite Toe Boot</li>
<li>Women - Ariat Terrain Pull-On Waterproof Boots</li>
<li>Durango Women's Waterproof Composite Toe Western Boot</li>
<li>Ariat Hybrid Rancher Waterproof Cowgirl Boot</li>
<li>Twisted X Women's Cowboy Work Boots</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<h2>Are cowboy boots typically warm?</h2>
<p><strong>In a nutshell, yes they are extremely warm. Due to their sturdy composition of high-grade leather, plus the inner lining, the height of the boots, and the thickness of the soles, they simply ooze warmth. This makes them very sought after in cold weather climates and months.</strong></p>
<p>Like we talked about earlier, cowboy boots might be a little too warm in summer months. However, they will still protect your feet and lower legs from the intense heat of the season. Not to mention, they will also offer solid protection from the hard atmospheric conditions of working on the range or a ranch. Therefore, you can still wear them in hot weather.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Waterproof Insulated Cowboy Boots</h2>
<p><strong>You may be wondering if the cost and effort of waterproofing cowboy boots is worth it. The answer is definitely yes. Think of how much you spent on the boots to begin with. Then think about all the wet weather you have wherever you live.</strong></p>
<p>Even if it doesn't literally snow much, it probably rains a lot. Rain is just as harmful to your boots as snow. Now think about the cost of repeatedly repairing your boots. Or how about having to buy a new pair every couple of years. Now ask yourself if waterproofing them is worth the money and time. We think you see our point!</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Final Thoughts</h2>
<p><strong>The whole point of this article is that, yes you can wear cowboy boots in the winter if you take proper precautions. If you have plenty of money to spend on new boots every couple of years, then you can ignore our advice. It is totally up to you!</strong></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>5 things to know about Cowboy boots with turned up toes</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/cowboy-boots-with-turned-up-toes/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/cowboy-boots-with-turned-up-toes/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-12T06:27:20-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Cowboy boots with turned up toes Perhaps you’re thinking of getting a pair of cowboy boots, or are just curious about all the different types and seeing what the fuss is all about. Whether you’re in it to wear them or just want a bit&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h2>Cowboy boots with turned up toes</h2>
<p>Perhaps you’re thinking of getting a pair of cowboy boots, or are just curious about all the different types and seeing what the fuss is all about.</p>
<p>Whether you’re in it to wear them or just want a bit of knowledge to satisfy that curious itch in your mind, know that cowboy boots are made for certain lifestyles.</p>
<p>This kind of footwear either provides comfort and versatility for rugged work, or makes a bold statement.</p>
<p>In this article, we’ll discuss why turned up toes are used for cowboy boots, why Mexicans find pointy boots so popular, and the different shapes that pointed cowboy boots can take.</p>
<h2><strong>Why do cowboy boots have turned-up toes? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>Traditionally, it’s to make horse-riding easier. </strong></p>
<p>That point on the boot is there, making it easier for horse riders to put their feet into stirrups.</p>
<p>In addition, a special angle around the ball of the foot is added so that the boots become locked in place once inserted.</p>
<p>Interestingly enough, this design originated as far back as <a href="https://artsandculture.google.com/story/the-high-life-a-history-of-men-in-heels/iQJCgMgwSKV5Kw">10th century</a> in the form of what we know today as high heels.</p>
<p>Originally, the high heel was used primarily by men, making it easier to ride horses, and to keep steady when firing arrows from their trusty steeds.</p>
<p>Even famous bands such as Motley Crue may have used them in many of their live performances.</p>
<p>Aside from practicality, pointed-toed boots are mostly used as a popular fashion choice.</p>
<p>Ever since the early 2000’s, pointed toe cowboy boots have become all the rage among western men and women alike.</p>
<h2><strong>What is the point of Mexican pointy boots? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>The short answer is popularity.</strong></p>
<p>Also called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mexican_pointy_boots">trival boots</a>, or “<em>botas tribaleras</em>” in Spanish, these kinds of footwear are mostly worn by Mexican men who take part in what’s referred to as “trival” music.</p>
<p>Also known as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tribal_guarachero">tribal guarachero</a>, this brand is a fusion of regional Mexican music genres and electronic dance music.</p>
<p>Whereas the actual origin of these boots remains uncertain, some sources state that trival boots came from the Mexican state of Nuevo Leon, Monterrey in 2009.</p>
<p>The style then spread to various areas in the US such as Oklahoma, Tennessee, Mississippi, and Dallas, Texas.</p>
<p>Aside from being an eye-catching fashion statement, guys who wear these boots participate in group dance-offs at local nightclubs.</p>
<p>Some groups take great effort into coordinating their moves, and can spend weeks on end to get their routines just right. This isn’t just for show either, the winning groups of these contests have been known to win up to $500 in prize money.</p>
<p>The more popular dance troupes have been hired to entertain for bachelorette parties and even weddings.</p>
<h2><strong>What are pointed toe cowboy boots called? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>It depends on the type of pointed toe.</strong></p>
<p>The pointed toe was originally made for versatility. Today, it serves much of the same function, and not just for getting your foot into a stirrup.</p>
<p>If a boot has a very sharp point, it’s referred to as <a href="https://stageswest.com/blog/how-to-choose-a-toe-shape-for-your-boots/">"needle pointed."</a>. If the toe has a tip that’s slightly blunted instead, it’s then referred to as a “snip toe.” Anything in-between those types is called “J toe.”</p>
<p>There’s also the <a href="https://www.ariat.com/al/cowboy-boots-square-toe-vs-pointed-toe">square toe</a>, a kind of boot that’s used for general outdoor work. Whereas the traditional pointed toe is used for both horse riding and formal events, the square toe can also be used as a dress boot as well as anything that involves constant walking.</p>
<p>Some other types include the cutter toe, the round toe, and the regular square. The name is defined as such, depending on the amount of foot space that each boot allows.</p>
<p>Should any of these kinds interest you, look at your own foot size to determine which kind of cowboy boot toe is best.</p>
<p>Anything with a pointy tip will usually be a bit tighter, and might require a certain level of swagger just to pull off.</p>
<p>If you’re looking for something more casual, it’s recommended that you pick a more blunt-tipped style of boot to allow more foot room, and therefore, more comfort.</p>
<p>Unless you’re a hardcore rancher or do a lot of horse-back riding, getting pointed tipped boots may not be a good idea. The thinner tip has been known to make general walking uncomfortable, so before you decide on buying a pair of any kind of cowboy boots, make sure you know what you’ll use them for.</p>
<h2><strong>Final thoughts</strong></h2>
<p>Now that you have equipped yourself with a bit more knowledge than you had before, you might be more confident in trying out some turned-up cowboy boots yourself. Or, if you’re bold enough, grab a pair of flashy trival boots and join a Mexican dancing troupe.</p>
<p>Whereas style is important for various reasons, pick a type that’s most comfortable for you and your purposes. You don’t want to find yourself out on the ranch or on the dance floor just to have your toes start aching with pain after an hour or so of use.</p>
<p>Regardless of your personality or reasons, know that the pointed tip on cowboy boots is there for a reason, and not just an expression of fashion. The style itself may change depending on cultural fads, or even to serve some practical purpose we are not yet aware of, but know that pointed toes will be hanging around for quite a while.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>What shoes to wear with cowboy hat (Explained)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/what-shoes-to-wear-with-cowboy-hat/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/what-shoes-to-wear-with-cowboy-hat/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-11T09:17:20-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Believe it or not, the answer to this question is varied. It is most common to wear boots with a cowboy hat, especially if they are cowboy boots. However, it is also fashionable to wear dress shoes or casual shoes with one, just not sandals.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><strong>Believe it or not, the answer to this question is varied. It is most common to wear boots with a cowboy hat, especially if they are cowboy boots. </strong></p>
<p><strong>However, it is also fashionable to wear dress shoes or casual shoes with one, just not sandals. It greatly depends on the occasion. For more information on this subject, keep reading this article. </strong></p>
<h2>How to match cowboy hat to boots</h2>
<p><strong>Is this important? In actuality, yes; but many people fail to do this, and they survive just fine. </strong></p>
<p><strong>Nobody really notices. Ideally though, you should wear a hat that matches your boots. Would you like some examples? </strong></p>
<p><strong>Keep reading!</strong></p>
<p>If it is a formal occasion, you want your hat and boot color to go with your suit jacket and pants.</p>
<p><a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/grey-suit-with-cowboy-boots/">They can either be a match or a complimentary contrasting color. In either case, you will want your hat and boots to match for the best look.</a></p>
<p>Technically, the material of the hat and boots should also match.</p>
<p>For instance, if you are wearing a suede cowboy hat, you would be best off wearing suede cowboy boots. People don't always pay attention to this rule.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Can you wear a cowboy hat with shoes?</h2>
<p><strong>It depends on whom you are dressing for. There are some purists who feel that wearing anything other than boots with a cowboy hat is a sin. The rest of the public does not feel this way and tends to ignore the purists.</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/black-suit-with-brown-cowboy-boots/">In essence, yes you can wear shoes with a cowboy hat; but the type of shoes you wear is relevant.</a></p>
<p>You can wear a nice pair of dress shoes and look extremely handsome. As we already mentioned though, wearing sandals is a no-no.</p>
<p>If you are working or riding on a horse when wearing a cowboy hat, nobody will give you flack if you wear sneakers. <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/what-are-the-best-jeans-to-wear-with-cowboy-boots/">You may look a little silly that way, but who cares if you are comfortable in them?</a> Wear sneakers or shoes if you want!</p>
<h2>Are there specific fashion rules for wearing dress shoes with a cowboy hat?</h2>
<p><strong>Once again, it depends on the occasion. </strong></p>
<p><strong>If it is a formal event, dress shoes should be worn. If the person would rather wear boots, then a dressy pair of cowboy boots is appropriate and looks fine to others.</strong></p>
<p>Another factor is where the person is. In much of American nowadays, a cowboy hat is seldom worn. <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/do-you-tuck-your-pants-in-cowboy-boots/">If someone in the northeastern United States is wearing one, they will likely be mocked.</a> Of course, if they are in either the west or southwest, it is common and revered.</p>
<p>Your best bet is to wear shoes with a material and a color to match your cowboy hat.</p>
<p><a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/do-you-tuck-your-pants-in-cowboy-boots/">This is extremely fashionable, and you will look quite dashing.</a></p>
<h2>Do you have to wear boots with a cowboy hat?</h2>
<p><strong>While it is not illegal not to wear the boots; fashion mavens insist that boots are a must if you are going to wear the cowboy hat. </strong></p>
<p><strong>Consider this! If you are wearing a black cowboy hat with black dress boots, you will look sensational. Especially if the hat and boots are made of leather or another fine material.</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/do-you-tuck-your-pants-in-cowboy-boots/">If you do not have a pair of boots, then a slick-looking pair of dress shoes of a similar style to the hat will do fine.</a></p>
<p>A more formal appearance will be achieved by wearing cowboy boots with a cowboy hat.</p>
<p>Please note, if you are wearing a boot of any other type than a cowboy boot when you are wearing a cowboy hat, some people might think you look ridiculous. <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/can-you-wear-a-fedora-with-cowboy-boots/">However, if you don't care what those people think, go ahead and wear them.</a></p>
<h2>What about women?</h2>
<p><strong>Generally the same fashion rules apply to a woman wearing shoes with a cowgirl hat as they do for men. </strong></p>
<p><strong>It depends on where she is as well as the occasion. Again, if she lives in the west or southwest, it is appropriate for her to wear a cowgirl hat. In that case, if she wants to wear shoes with it, dressier kinds look best.</strong></p>
<p>On the other hand, if she lives anyplace else, she might look rather silly in a cowgirl hat. However, the United States is a free country. So, if she chooses to wear one anyhow, that is her right and nobody will ever stop her.</p>
<p><a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/grey-suit-with-cowboy-boots/">As with the men, if a woman wants to appear as a fashion plate, she should wear cowgirl boots with a cowgirl hat.</a> She should try to match the colors and material types for the best look possible.</p>
<h2>Where is it normal to wear a cowboy hat?</h2>
<p><strong>As we have been alluding to, this completely depends on where he is and the occasion. If a man of the west is attending a formal occasion, then wearing a cowboy hat with his attire IS dressing up. In this case, he would wear an especially fine hat. Chances are he owns a number of cowboy hats anyhow, one for each purpose.</strong></p>
<p>It is also prudent to wear one while performing his cowboy duties on the range or a ranch. Normally, this would be while riding his or her horse. <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/do-you-tuck-your-pants-in-cowboy-boots/">In such a case, he should wear work-oriented cowboy boots with the rest of his outfit.</a></p>
<h2>Final Thoughts</h2>
<p><strong>Keep in mind, even at casual events but especially at formal ones, it is proper etiquette to remove the hat upon entering the building or room. </strong></p>
<p><strong>This is true of any type of hat in addition to a cowboy one. It is also okay to wear shoes when wearing the cowboy hat as long as they are meant for that level of formality. </strong></p>
<p><strong>Again, this is a free country. If you want to wear the shoes with the hat, go right ahead!</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>5 Things To Know About Wearing A Grey suit with cowboy boots</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/grey-suit-with-cowboy-boots/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/grey-suit-with-cowboy-boots/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-11T06:34:00-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Grey suit with cowboy boots You want to dress for success. Or you want to dress for a night of fun, but you want to look good in front of all your friends, family, and peers. Despite dressing for formality or just wanting to let&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h2 class="p1">Grey suit with cowboy boots<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></h2>
<p>You want to dress for success. Or you want to dress for a night of fun, but you want to look good in front of all your friends, family, and peers. Despite dressing for formality or just wanting to let off a bit of steam, looking good can make you <em>feel</em> good.</p>
<p>An important occasion is coming up, and you want to try out some cowboy boots and a grey suit combination. Yet, is the combo you have in your mind the best choice? What will others think? Worry not, for we’ll discuss which boots can work with grey suits, and the fine details that will bring out the style <em>and</em> confidence.</p>
<h2><strong>How can you pair cowboy boots with a grey suit? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>The answer lies in your attitude.</strong></p>
<p>The question you should be asking yourself isn’t whether your clothes are worthy of you, it’s if <em>you’re</em> worthy of your clothes. When pairing <em>any</em> suit with cowboy boots, how you carry yourself matters.</p>
<p>Wearing both a suit and cowboy boots outside of Texas is described as a: <a href="https://www.dmarge.com/how-to-wear-boots-with-suit">"big and bold statement."</a> If you haven’t already, brush up on your swagger.</p>
<p>If you’re feeling a bit overwhelmed at the moment, don’t sweat, because you don't need the charisma of a Country Super star just to pull off the look you’re going for. What can help you in the short term is learning how to <a href="https://www.wikihow.com/Walk-with-Confidence">walk with confidence</a>. Once you practice this advice often enough, you’ll start to feel <em>great</em> in your grey suit and cowboy boots combo. With enough time and effort, others will start to notice as well, and admire you for it.</p>
<h2><strong>Should you wear a grey suit with cowboy boots? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>You can, if you know how to pull it off.</strong></p>
<p>Now you’re asking yourself not if you can pull off the grey suit and boots, but <em>should</em> you? Having a confident attitude may be important to achieve it, but don’t skip the details as well. Specifically, suit accessories such as the right shirt and tie.</p>
<p>A great choice of shirt to go with whichever hue of grey suit you own is a white one. However, it’s not the only color that can work. Navy, pink, and blue are all colors that will pair nicely with grey. Whichever your choice, the shirt should look clean and crisp. Take your time to give it a good wash, optional bleach, and a solid ironing to make it look the best.</p>
<p>Next up is the tie. Again, the color is what you should focus on. Popular choices include “true blue,” maroon, forest green, and red.</p>
<p>The shading can matter too, as you want your tie to stand out (you’re working on your swagger, remember?), so whichever shirt/tie combination you choose, if one is dark, the other should be lighter.</p>
<h2><strong>What color boots go well with a grey suit? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>Options are a bit limited, but you can be flexible with them.</strong></p>
<p>It’s more than likely that the most important piece is the cowboy boots themselves. For grey suits, it’s recommended you go with either brown, cherry black, or plain black for the boot color.</p>
<p>Darker colors might be better in the case of a <em>light</em> grey suit. Darker grey suits can pair well with brown shoes, as the hues will be similar and won’t risk a color clash.</p>
<p>On an important note, these colors can also be used on different kinds of boots altogether. We’ll touch up on that a bit later.</p>
<p><strong>Bonus content: There are other types of boots!</strong></p>
<p>You’re your own boss, so whichever pair of boots you want to wear on your feet, that’s that. However, that being said, it’s always a good idea to expand your options.</p>
<p>For example, you can go with a nice-looking pair of oxfords, <a href="https://www.wikihow.com/Walk-with-Confidence">"capped toes"</a>, or even your own dress shoes (if you already own a pair), as long as they are burgundy or black. Consider doing this instead if your cowboy boots are bright in color.</p>
<p>Other options that will work great with a grey suit are <a href="https://www.amazon.ca/Clarks-Mens-Chukka-Nubuc-Numeric_10_Point_5/dp/B08FVHXL8L/ref=asc_df_B08FVHXL8L/?tag=googleshopc0c-20&amp;linkCode=df0&amp;hvadid=570082828694&amp;hvpos=&amp;hvnetw=g&amp;hvrand=17643113985851333354&amp;hvpone=&amp;hvptwo=&amp;hvqmt=&amp;hvdev=c&amp;hvdvcmdl=&amp;hvlocint=&amp;hvlocphy=9001319&amp;hvtargid=pla-1434520040774&amp;psc=1">Chukka boots</a>, and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Generic1-Chelsea-Anti-Slip-Waterproof-Business/dp/B08Y8RHVS7">Chelsea</a>-style footwear. These types have been known to be more “stylish,” meaning they’re great for formal occasions.</p>
<p>If you <a href="https://www.dmarge.com/how-to-wear-boots-with-suit">tailor your dress pants</a> right, you can try out boots made by RM Williams. Just another side note, that’s another thing you should iron and clean correctly, because gaining confidence can be hard when everyone’s smiling at all your pant crinkles.</p>
<p>Whichever of these you think is the best second choice, it’s recommended that you get a pair that’s in leather.</p>
<p>Leather, especially polished, tends to have a more refined look whenever it’s paired with a suit. Bonus points if you can do that with lighter colors, such as brown.</p>
<p>When it comes down to it, cowboy boots are fine. Just don’t forget that you have other options.</p>
<h2><strong>Final Thoughts</strong></h2>
<p>Whereas the suit can make the man, the man can also make the suit. If you’ve looked at yourself many times in the mirror with your chosen combo and still don’t approve, at least try walking inside your home for a while. Keep your chin up, and eyes straight ahead.</p>
<p>If you can, get some of your buddies to dress the same! Being around people you’re familiar with can help shrug off some of the nervous feelings while in public. You’re just trying to make a fashion statement, not attend a funeral.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Want To Wear Cowboy Boots Under Wedding Dress? 5 Tips To Follow</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/cowboy-boots-under-wedding-dress/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/cowboy-boots-under-wedding-dress/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-11T06:34:06-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    A wedding can be the most important moment in a woman’s life. On top of all the invitations, plans, catering, she also has to carefully consider what she wears. Not only does she want her future husband impressed and love-struck with awe by her appearance,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>A wedding can be the most important moment in a woman’s life.</p>
<p>On top of all the invitations, plans, catering, she also has to carefully consider what she wears. Not only does she want her future husband impressed and love-struck with awe by her appearance, she wants the wedding guests to be amazed too!</p>
<p>In this article, we’ll discuss whether wearing cowboy boots underneath a wedding dress is appropriate, and ways in which the combination can work.</p>
<h2><strong>Can you wear cowboy boots underneath a wedding dress? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>Yes you can, just be aware of the terrain!</strong></p>
<p>The real heart of the issue isn’t whether you <em>can</em> wear cowboy boots to your wedding or not. Just about anyone can wear boots anytime they please. It’s a matter of your personal choices and the environment.</p>
<p>Let’s talk a bit about practicality.</p>
<p>If you’re having your wedding in the great outdoors, within a rustic barn, or even nearby horse stables (these are just examples, the style of the wedding is up to you), wearing cowboy boots will not only be theme-appropriate, but will also prevent you from spraining your ankle during the ceremony.</p>
<p>Traditional wedding footwear such as high-heels won’t function very well on dirt, gravel, mud, or grass.</p>
<p>If you have to spend large amounts of time outside on rugged terrain during your special event, consider slipping on your best pair of cowboy boots for both function and form.</p>
<p>Whereas rugged boots might seem more of a masculine approach, keep in mind the ground that you’ll be walking on.</p>
<p>Nature isn’t known to have smooth, flat surfaces for treading, so it might be a good idea to wear something that will carry you in comfort, especially during an event as important as your wedding.</p>
<h2><strong>Should you wear cowboy boots underneath a wedding dress? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>Again, wearing or not wearing them is a matter of choice.</strong></p>
<p>In our western world, the bride has <em>a huge</em> influence over choosing what goes into a wedding. If you’re already considering wearing cowboy boots for your special day, go ahead!</p>
<p>Heck, you could even ask all your friends and family to do the same!</p>
<p>Choosing to wear them is also a matter of confidence. Does it feel fun to wear cowboy boots?</p>
<p>Do you love country dancing on the dance floor all night long? If any of the previous questions gets you excited, then cowboy boots are a perfect choice!</p>
<p>You don’t have to be wild and crazy just to appreciate them either. As mentioned earlier, the wedding theme is important too.</p>
<p>Should the background match, taking pictures with your stylish boots will leave you and your family with fun memories for years to come.</p>
<p>Another reminder, the ground you’ll be walking on should be considered as well. No bride wants to stumble all over the place because she didn’t wear something functional enough.</p>
<p>To save yourself from any potential embarrassment (or worse, serious harm), make sure the footwear you choose, cowboy boots or whatever else, is practical enough to serve your wishes.</p>
<h2><strong>What cowboy boots can go well with a wedding dress? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>It’s recommended you choose style over function, and there are multiple options to pick from. </strong></p>
<p>With that being said, at the very least, whatever pair of dress boots you choose, test them on uneven ground should the need arise.</p>
<p>Even though Lacey boots are more appropriate for weddings, they should come with a degree of toughness as well.</p>
<p>If you’re willing to go all out on the looks, try shopping for some custom-made boots that the <a href="https://www.amazon.ca/s?k=Lucchese+cowboy+boots&amp;linkCode=gs3&amp;linkId=23c75ae5e2be718d98b8c10b83e4865e&amp;tag=asset1048ca00-20">Lucchese</a> brand is well-known for.</p>
<p>However, keep in mind that the price tag for this kind of footwear is expensive, and can be thousands of dollars for a single pair!</p>
<p>For those on a budget, or simply don’t want to dish out a couple grand just for some wedding boots, <a href="https://www.amazon.ca/s?k=justin+cowboy+boots&amp;linkCode=gs3&amp;linkId=817631ea4271a54c9f91f7d5e88d4f12&amp;tag=asset1048ca00-20">Justin</a> and <a href="https://www.amazon.ca/s?k=Corral+cowboy+boots&amp;linkCode=gs3&amp;linkId=c5f27c15c9ddca31c9cc03855a4fa856&amp;tag=asset1048ca00-20">Corral</a> are decent brands to consider as well.</p>
<p>Both these companies offer boots that are tough, stylish, and affordable.</p>
<p>If you’re still unsure, pick multiple pairs that you think would go great with your wedding attire, and ask some of your close family members and friends for their opinions.</p>
<p>It helps to not only feel great in your cowboy boots, but also be <em>seen</em> in them as well.</p>
<h2><strong>Will a short wedding dress look good with cowboy boots?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Yes, yes it would.</strong></p>
<p>A short wedding dress will not only show off your boots more, but it’s highly recommended that you do so for this purpose. What’s the point of wearing cowboy boots in the first place if your dress is too long for others to see?</p>
<p>To get more specific, the type of short dress you’ll choose can matter.</p>
<p>The appropriate length should be about mid-calf hemline or knee-length.</p>
<p>For overall style, consider picking a lace or western-style dress that will compliment your chosen pair of cowboy boots. If the combination looks great, feels great, and elicits compliments from your friends and family, then you’ve found the right look!</p>
<h2><strong>Final Thoughts</strong></h2>
<p>It’s <em>your</em> special day, the final choice of what you wear is what you want the most.</p>
<p>Aside from the choices already mentioned, you can also check out this <a href="https://bridalmusings.com/175679/boot-barn-cowboy-boots-for-your-wedding/">website</a>, or even this <a href="https://www.bootbarn.com/womens/featured/wedding-collection/?utm_source=PR&amp;utm_medium=PR_Placement&amp;utm_campaign=BridalCampaign_BridalMusings_JUNE">one</a> for more options on how to make your western wedding dreams come true. There’s even a simple <a href="http://mckinneyswesternstore.com/wear-cowboy-boots-wedding-dress/">guide</a> you can use to make your wedding the best day it can be.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Black suit with brown cowboy boots | CAN IT BE DONE?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/black-suit-with-brown-cowboy-boots/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/black-suit-with-brown-cowboy-boots/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-10T15:22:09-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    In this article we are going to tell you why it is fine to wear a black suit with brown cowboy boots. We will answer a few other relevant questions as well. Make sure you read it all the way through. The simple answer is&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><strong>In this article we are going to tell you why it is fine to wear a black suit with brown cowboy boots. We will answer a few other relevant questions as well. Make sure you read it all the way through.</strong></p>
<h2>Can you wear brown cowboy boots with black suit?</h2>
<p><strong>The simple answer is yes, you can. However, there are a couple of fashion rules that apply here. They make the difference as to how the brown cowboy boots can be worn with a black suit. So, what are these rules? Let's take a look.</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/is-vaseline-good-for-cowboy-boots/">First, the shade of brown makes a huge difference. It is important to choose a darker shade.</a> A lighter shade of brown or a tan boot simply will not work. When selecting the rest of the outfit, keep things on a monochromatic level. Not only will this make your overall look better, it will make the darker brown cowboy boots stand out.</p>
<p>The other rule is, it depends on where you are wearing this combination. Is it a social occasion? A business meeting or a day at the office? An occasion that calls for an elegant appearance? <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/do-you-tuck-your-pants-in-cowboy-boots/">If the answer to any of these questions is yes, you can wear the brown cowboy boots.</a> However, they should be a dressier style.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Should you wear a black suit with brown cowboy boots?</h2>
<p><strong>The safer bet is to wear black cowboy boots with the black suit. That is why most men choose this combination. However, when the specific style of cowboy boot fits the occasion, a dark brown color looks quite fine. In fact, it is rather dashing.</strong></p>
<p>Something that matters here is if the suit is a solid black, or it has pinstripes on it. If it does, you would be best off wearing a black boot. It can be a stylish cowboy boot though. <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/sports-coat-with-jeans-and-cowboy-boots/">If you want to be daring though, a freshly-shined dark brown boot would look very spiffy with such a suit.</a></p>
<p>The material of the suit can also be a factor in determining the color and style of shoes or boots to wear. According to the fashion gurus, a black linen suit would look fabulous with brown cowboy boots.</p>
<h2>When should you consider wearing a black suit with brown cowboy boots?</h2>
<p><strong>There are many occasions where a black suit with brown cowboy boots are appropriate. Not only for men, but for women wearing a black pants suit for that special occasion. Like when? Keep reading.</strong></p>
<p>This combination can be worn to political events. Over the years, even presidents have done this. Other times you will see people in mariachi bands wearing them. Law enforcement officers tend to sport this look when attending special events. You might think of rangers in western states like Texas.</p>
<p><a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/how-to-keep-cowboy-boots-from-rubbing-leg/">Fashion trends have come a long way in the past few decades. Whereas it used to be a fashion faux pas to wear a combination like that, today it is widely accepted. </a>Go ahead and wear them.</p>
<h2>What color suit goes with brown cowboy boots?</h2>
<p><strong>There are more colors than you might think that will look terrific with brown cowboy boots. You can try different shades of blue, darker green colors, beige or tan suits too. How about a nice charcoal gray suit with them? That would look stunning and very manly.</strong></p>
<p>One tip to remember is, the fancier the suit is, both in color and material, the fancier the boots should be. Imagine your cowboy boots in a dark brown snake skin or alligator hide. <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/black-suit-with-brown-cowboy-boots/">Don't laugh, we are serious! Not only can you find boots like that, but they'll make you appear sensational.</a></p>
<p>Another option for the material of your brown cowboy boots is a nice, smooth suede. Oh, how handsome you will be in those. If your suit color is also brown, your boots will enhance your overall appearance.</p>
<h2>Is it OK to wear boots with a suit?</h2>
<p><strong>As we discussed earlier, nowadays, that is a more hip fashion trend. Decades ago it would have been frowned upon, but today it is fine. Again, it depends on the occasion. </strong></p>
<p>What about a woman wearing boots with her pantsuit? We touched on that briefly too. Basically, it is now acceptable if the circumstances are right. It has to be the right event and the pantsuit is not too formal.</p>
<p>With men or women, they should remember that a snazzy pair of cowboy boots in the right style is just as dressy as a pair of dress shoes. They are probably more comfortable too. So, wear the boots with your suit. You are bound to receive compliments.</p>
<h2>Final Thoughts</h2>
<p><strong>There is nothing like owning a pair of genuine cowboy boots in brown. For that matter, you can own a couple of them in various materials and styles. Then you will have a pair for any occasion that arises.</strong></p>
<p><strong>You don't even need to live in the west to own fine cowboy boots. If no store sells it locally, get them over the Internet. Just be sure you know your correct size. Your friends will marvel over how nice they look. Your business clients will be impressed too. So, what is stopping you from buying a pair right now?</strong></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Is vaseline good for cowboy boots? (Explained)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/is-vaseline-good-for-cowboy-boots/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/is-vaseline-good-for-cowboy-boots/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-10T06:04:35-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Is vaseline good for cowboy boots Wearing a slick pair of cowboy boots can make you feel great, and if worn appropriately, you’ll gain the approval of others too. Yet, like all things that you wear, those stylish boots will eventually break down. How do&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h2 class="p1">Is vaseline good for cowboy boots</h2>
<p>Wearing a slick pair of cowboy boots can make you feel great, and if worn appropriately, you’ll gain the approval of others too.</p>
<p>Yet, like all things that you wear, <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/what-are-the-best-jeans-to-wear-with-cowboy-boots/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">those stylish boots will eventually break down.</a></p>
<p>How do you delay the ravages of time itself? Someone tells you that Vaseline can do the trick…but is that stuff good for boots in general? In this article, <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/do-you-tuck-your-pants-in-cowboy-boots/">we’ll take a look at this product</a> and what it can do for that favorite pair of leather cowboy boots of yours.</p>
<h2><strong>Can I use Vaseline on my boots? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>Yes you can. </strong></p>
<p>Using a little bit of Vaseline can go a long way. Also known as “petroleum jelly,” Vaseline provides many benefits for just about all leather products.</p>
<p>Seeing how leather is a treated animal skin, Vaseline will react to it similarly to human skin. Some of these benefits include: removing scuffs and scratches, preventing cracking, and providing a bit of cleaning.</p>
<h2><strong>How do you treat leather cowboy boots?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Use diligent care. </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/do-pants-go-over-or-under-cowboy-boots/">The process can differ </a>whether you’re treating newer vs. older leather boots of any kind. Cowboy boots are no exception.</p>
<p>As with any leather, your boots will require cleaning after a while.</p>
<p>A simple way to do this is using a nylon brush and a water-based cleaning agent on the <em>outside </em>of your boot. The inside might require a <a href="https://www.constructiongear.com/caring-for-your-work-boots.html">low PH</a> shampoo and careful rinsing.</p>
<p>Should your boots be older, you might have to do a lot more scrubbing depending on the buildup of whatever you gathered on them over the years.</p>
<p>Plus, it’s likely that you also added oil-based protection during that time, which will have to be scrubbed off too.</p>
<p>For newer boots, you might want to consider adding a leather-conditioner to prevent future wear and tear. Specific areas that need this are any part that will experience a lot of flexing while you wear your boots.</p>
<p>For either, it’s recommended that you add a water-based agent to water-proof your footwear. We will discuss that in more detail a bit later.</p>
<h2><strong>Will Vaseline ruin leather?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>It can if you use it too often.</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://favoredleather.com/is-petroleum-jelly-good-for-leather/">One source</a> cites “Petroleum Jelly may breakdown the tensile strength of the leather.” Simply put, Vaseline makes the cells within the leather itself swell and expand, causing deformities in your boots.</p>
<p>Seeing as you have to constantly apply it to keep the benefits of using Vaseline in the first place, it’s risky to use this product more than three times a year. In some cases, some boots have been known to “rot” on occasion.</p>
<h2><strong>Can you use Vaseline to waterproof leather boots? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>You can, but only temporarily. </strong></p>
<p>If the need to waterproof is urgent, Vaseline will help you right away. </p>
<p>To keep your skin moisturized, it “forms a barrier and prevents water from leaving your skin,” meaning it will have the same effect with leather.</p>
<p>That barrier will also prevent outside water from getting <em>in</em>.</p>
<p>However, this should only be for short-term use. There are better products out there that can water-proof those slick boots without the need for a quick-fix.</p>
<h2><strong>What is the best thing to put on leather boots? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>Don’t worry, you have options.</strong></p>
<p>As mentioned earlier, if you need a quick-fix regardless, go with Vaseline. If you apply it enough <a href="https://workgearz.com/can-vaseline-be-used-to-protect-leather-work-boots/">correctly</a>, it will help.</p>
<p>For the longer term, you can use a variety of products that include water-based agents that have <a href="https://www.constructiongear.com/caring-for-your-work-boots.html">no petroleum</a>, such as various <a href="https://campingsecrets.co.uk/best-product-for-waterproofing-leather-boots/">waxes and sprays</a>. Also, don’t forget that leather conditioners can help too.</p>
<p>The best you can do for your cowboy boots is keep track of them. Boots are not all that different from anything else people wear on their feet. What your own footwear will go through depends on what you use it for. Are you a rancher? Might want to clean those once every <a href="https://www.shoepassion.com/shoe-encyclopedia/shoe-care/how-to-clean-your-shoes/">two to three weeks</a>. If you’re using boots as formal wear, maybe not as often.</p>
<p>Also, take a look at your own habits.</p>
<p>Do you dance with them? Do you use them in the mud? Or are they only for indoors? Where you wear them matters too. You don’t have to treat your cowboys like a beloved pet, but give them a good look once in a while. They at least need attention.</p>
<h2><strong>Final Thoughts</strong></h2>
<p>To recap, keep in mind that Vaseline can water-proof, preserve, and even clean them a bit if you apply it right.</p>
<p>If you need them to last a while, your best bet will be to apply better long-term products.</p>
<p>Regardless of which combination of the above you choose to go, at the very least be consistent in whatever you do. Keep in mind that your cowboy boots are basically pieces of clothing that need cleaning and care.</p>
<p><em>Some</em> Vaseline may be okay, other times, not so much. If your boots are already deformed, maybe avoid using that stuff.</p>
<p>For cleaning, don’t leave them dirty for too long. Got mounds of muck and dirt? Scrub your boots like you mean it. Not a speck of dust?</p>
<p>Apply a long-term water-based agent. These are only just a few examples. Ultimately, you’ll need to spend time and effort finding the right practice.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>What are the best jeans to wear with cowboy boots? (Explained)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/what-are-the-best-jeans-to-wear-with-cowboy-boots/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/what-are-the-best-jeans-to-wear-with-cowboy-boots/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-10T06:37:58-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    There are a lot of styles of cowboy jeans available out there. Knowing how to find the right fit to match your cowboy boots is crucial. In fact, your cowboy jeans have evolved so much over the years. This means that choosing what works for&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are a lot of styles of cowboy jeans available out there. Knowing how to find the right fit to match your cowboy boots is crucial. In fact, your cowboy jeans have evolved so much over the years.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This means that choosing what works for you should coincide with fashion trends and style rules. Having a style guide to make it easier for you to choose your best pair of cowboy jeans should be a great thing. Keep reading to find out more about the best jeans to wear with your cowboy boots.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">What are the best jeans to wear with cowboy boots?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are various styles of jeans that are most suitable for cowboy boots.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Denim jeans make the best pair of cowboy boots. Since these boots are an effortless style choice, the following are great options to wear them.</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Skinny jeans</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bootcut jeans</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cropped jeans</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Denim shorts</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cowboy cut jeans</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Straight leg jeans</span></li>
</ul>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">How should jeans fit with cowboy boots?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Generally, the jeans should be long enough to cover the shaft of your cowboy boots while ensuring that your legs are protected.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ideally, when you’re choosing your jeans, it's essential to ensure that you find the right fit with great length. <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/sports-coat-with-jeans-and-cowboy-boots/">These should rest approximately half an inch above the heel of your boots. Additionally, make sure that the jeans aren’t tucked into your boots.</a></span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Why is the type of jeans important for cowboy boots?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The main reasons are to provide comfort and protection.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The thing is that cowboy boots are made for walking on unstructured terrain. There is a great deal of debris and other foreign objects that can snag on your jeans. Protecting your legs is important.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">When to consider choosing the right pair of jeans for cowboy boots?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/can-you-wear-a-fedora-with-cowboy-boots/">If you’re going to be working on a ranch or riding horses all day.</a></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The fact of the matter is that cowboys tend to do a lot of heavy lifting. Moreover, you’ll spend most of your time with various animals. The jeans that you choose should be well-fitted, durable, and comfortable.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Who should be paying attention to the type of jeans for their boots?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cowboys should be paying attention to the type of jeans that they choose to wear for their boots.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, anyone who spends an adequate amount of time outdoors should also consider the types of jeans that they were. If you spend a lot of time in a ranch, you’ll be exposed to a lot of debris. You should buy durable jeans to protect your boots as well as your legs from dirt.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Where can you go to find the best pair of jeans for some cowboy boots?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In most retail shops.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s easy for you to find a great pair of cowboy jeans. <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/how-to-get-a-stuck-cowboy-boot-off/">The most important thing is for you to have an idea of the type of jeans that you want to buy.</a> You can shop for your cowboy jeans online or you can go directly to a shop near you.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since you have a wide range of fits and styles to choose from, finding the best pair of cowboy jeans should be relatively easy for you. Even if you’re a beginner.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;"> How much longer should jeans be for cowboy boots?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Long enough to cover the heels of your boots.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ideally, the longer your jeans, the better they are. When you’re buying cowboy jeans, going for something longer instead of shorter is a great option. In fact, choosing jeans that are at least a quarter to an inch above your boots is what’s recommended.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Should jeans stack on cowboy boots?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yes, jeans should stack on your cowboy boots.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s recommended that you should have a minor stack in the leg of your cowboy jeans. Especially when you choose to wear them with your cowboy boots. This is why getting the right fit for your jeans is significant. <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/what-are-the-best-jeans-to-wear-with-cowboy-boots/">Finding jeans that are the right length that can rest just above your heels is what’s ideal.</a></span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do Cowboys wear their pants over their boots?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Not anymore.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Back in the days there were many cowboys who would tuck their pants inside their boots. This was a way to prevent any dirt from forming at the helm of their jeans. In addition, this was a good way to help prevent their jeans from catching any sticks or snagging on the fence.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But, times have changed and more and more cowboys prefer to wear their pants over their boots. Mainly, this helps to give a slight stack when the cowboy jeans fit well.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Can you wear slim jeans with cowboy boots?</span></h2>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yes, you can.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The thing about cowboy jeans is that they come in different styles. Some people prefer to not stack their jeans. Instead, they choose to tuck in their jeans. <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/what-color-cowboy-hat-to-wear-with-brown-boots/">Slim or skinny jeans are a better option because they can fit better inside if you want to tuck them inside.</a></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In summary, a lot of thought should go into the type of cowboy jeans that you choose. There are various styles that you can choose from. <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/do-you-tuck-your-pants-in-cowboy-boots/">Moreover, the type of lifestyle that you live should also influence what jeans you wear.</a></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When you’re thinking of cowboy jeans that should go with your cowboy boots, you should also think of the length. <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/is-vaseline-good-for-cowboy-boots/">Even though people do wear cowboy boots with denim shorts, it’s always a great idea to go for a longer length. </a>This not only plays a vital role in protecting your legs, but it also helps you to have a slight stack that’s fashionably recommended.</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Do you tuck your pants in cowboy boots? (Explained)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Texas Walkabout</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://texaswalkabout.com/do-you-tuck-your-pants-in-cowboy-boots/"/>
        <id>https://texaswalkabout.com/do-you-tuck-your-pants-in-cowboy-boots/</id>
            <category term="Western Wear"/>
            <category term="Cowboy Boots"/>

        <updated>2022-03-10T06:38:55-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Over the previous few years, fashion trends have altered dressing patterns. These trends are having an increasing impact on our appearance. This essay will go through the style of tucking pants into cowboy boots, why you should do it, what it means, and who should&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over the previous few years, fashion trends have altered dressing patterns. These trends are having an increasing impact on our appearance. This essay will go through the style of tucking pants into cowboy boots, why you should do it, what it means, and who should do it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tucking pants into boots is one of the debatable trends in the fashion world. This debate, however, is not as straightforward as it may appear.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do you tuck your pants in cowboy boots?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In my opinion, the genders of individuals greatly influence their decision to tuck in their pants or not. I tuck my pants into my cowboy boots only when necessary.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Females seem more likely to tuck in their boots. Tucked-up pants are more fashionable for females when the pants are skinny and fit snugly in cowboy boots. That said, it is advisable not to tuck in boot cuts. The extra fabric looks out of place and blows about in the wind.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a male, I rarely tuck my pants into my boots. Males tend to tuck in their pants when needed. Some people feel that males look ridiculous when they wear tuck-up pants purely out of fashion. Functionality plays a tremendous role for males.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Why should you tuck your pants inside cowboy boots?</span></h2>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">People tuck their pants in for several reasons, including bug control, cleanliness, and staying trendy. For females, being fashionable may rank high on a list of reasons. Tucked-in pants serve a practical purpose for both men and women.</span></p>
<p><strong>Pest-control measures:</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bug bites can be a concern depending on where you are. Bugs can crawl underneath the jeans and bite people on their legs if the pants don't get tucked in. This isn't going to be a pleasant experience. Tucked-in pants solve this problem because bugs can't reach the skin of the leg through the openings.</span></p>
<p><strong>Ensures clean pants:</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When people tuck their pants into their boots, they don't care if the bottoms of their pants get filthy. The boots keep the pants from getting soiled, and the wearer is relieved of the burden of washing. <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/is-vaseline-good-for-cowboy-boots/">People who operate in muddy settings are well aware of the difficulty of washing filthy pants.</a></span></p>
<p><strong>Demonstrates your high-end fashion sense:</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">People sometimes like to brag about how pricey their boots are. Beautiful needlework and boot labels are typically hidden high up and can get hidden if an individual maintains his pants untucked. <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/what-are-the-best-jeans-to-wear-with-cowboy-boots/">When individuals purchase well-known designer boots, they will undoubtedly want to flaunt them.</a></span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">What does it mean when you tuck your pants in your boots?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tucking pants into cowboy boots entails tucking the pants' lower legs into the boot. This action is done so that the pants do not come undone when the wearer is doing various activities.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The pants should be slim but not very tight. The leg opening of the jeans should be narrow so that it does not come undone. Bootcuts or flared pants should be avoided (in general, but especially for tucking into boots.)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You should wear boots taller than your ankles and have enough room inside for your jeans. <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/do-pants-go-over-or-under-cowboy-boots/">The pants can easily slide into the boots with such space.</a></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">People that wear their pants tucked into cowboy boots see themselves as confident, rakish, and unconcerned about their surroundings.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Who should be tucking their pants inside of cowboy boots?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Almost everyone can tuck their pants in. For some groups of people, however, it is more common. This wearing style is more prevalent among models and cowboys. Here are a few examples of folks who should tuck their jeans into cowboy boots:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Models who desire to keep a fashionable, confident appearance</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Those who labor outside, particularly in bug-infested locations</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cowboys and farmers who operate in a filthy environment.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/sports-coat-with-jeans-and-cowboy-boots/">Riders who don't want their pants' loose free ends to catch on the saddle.</a></span></li>
</ul>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final thoughts</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tucking pants into cowboy boots requires tucking the lower legs of the pants into the boot. Bug control, cleanliness, and being fashionable are among the reasons why people tuck their pants in. <a href="https://texaswalkabout.com/sports-coat-with-jeans-and-cowboy-boots/">Males, like myself, should only tuck their jeans into cowboy boots when necessary. Among many professions, models and cowboys are more likely to dress in this manner.</a></span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
